I'm here, I'm here.
Oh my god.
I made it.
I thought I could make a quick trip to the store while I was, you know, while the countdown was happening.
Because I realized I didn't have a drink!
So I had to improvise a little bit.
I ran to the store.
Because my bike is out of commission right now.
The tire is flat.
And the chain is off the... wheel.
It's off the chain, I guess.
Hey, that's where that expression comes from.
Huh, I never thought about that.
That makes so much sense.
Saying someone is off their chain, you know?
It's... yeah, okay.
Well, cheers!
What's the music?
It is Persona 5 music!
One of the greatest tracks ever.
It's called A Woman.
Oh, man.
Never heard of that before you made that up?
I didn't make it up!
That's real, son!
Would I lie to you?
Me, of all people, I would never lie.
I'm past all that.
I had a little period with lying, but nowadays...
No more lying.
That song is not real.
It is.
It's entirely real.
Ah, man.
Guys, I have done it.
I have actually, finally...
...reached my end-game computer setup.
There's nothing more to improve.
I'm happy now.
It's perfect.
I had fiber-optic cables running to my living room now, where my computer is.
It is super quiet in here.
There is no heat being generated.
The AC is installed.
It doesn't get better.
This is my setup.
If nothing breaks, I will have this setup for 20 years.
We did it.
No matter what, it can't get hot in here.
Except, of course, maybe the monitor gives off a little heat, but fuck that shit.
I don't care about that.
It is perfect now.
Nothing more to improve.
That's where my money goes.
It doesn't go towards a car, or a mortgage, or a girlfriend, or something like that.
I have my priorities, okay?
That's what I choose to spend my money on.
Oh!
Jackie is also gonna reach her end-game setup soon.
I bought her a couple more things for the wall.
I bought her a little hammock that she can lie in.
I have to install it, though.
And some more scratching things on the wall.
Soon we will both be end-game.
And it's gonna be amazing.
Yeah, end-game as in, you know, there's nothing else to do now.
Now we reach the end.
Now I can finally play the game of life, you know?
Would you ever play multiplayer?
You mean in real life?
Ah.
Maybe.
Girlfriend when.
Ah, I don't know.
That's not really part of my end-game.
Not right now, at least.
I wanna see your setup.
Maybe I'll do a video on it, actually.
What's up, Diego?
Is it hot over there?
Claire, is that you?
No, listen.
Claire was an incident that we don't talk about anymore.
Claire is, you know...
It is what it is.
I have no part in that.
Jackie gets a partner when.
She has me!
Is that right, Jackie?
She is sound asleep.
She doesn't even react to me anymore.
Wow.
Very hot here.
Italy.
Oh, right, you're there now.
I thought you were in Chile for some reason.
I can imagine.
But at least you don't have a lot of humidity, I imagine, right?
It's better over there with the humidity, at least.
Are you gonna watch the eclipse?
Wait, what eclipse?
Is there an eclipse?
When does that happen?
Eclipse.
Wednesdays...
Wait, really?
Oh, shit!
Wait, when is that?
I am not keeping up with this at all.
7pm?
But...
Can I even see it from Denmark?
I guess I can just check.
Oh, you're right.
Partial.
Nice!
Oh yeah, I'm definitely looking at that.
Thanks for telling me!
I didn't know!
I appreciate it.
Yeah, 70% is pretty good.
90% from UK?
Where's the full eclipse?
Probably over some water somewhere.
Is it really too astrophysics or it's just a long-running joke?
It's a long-running joke.
It's not real.
We made it up entirely.
Remember when I told you I lied?
I lie all the time.
I lie on my CV.
I lie about everything I do.
In fact, I didn't even get the fiber-optics cables.
I lied about that.
It's all sitting on a cardboard right now.
It's terrible.
The co-worker is the astrophysics vlog was a paid actor.
Yeah, that's not even me!
That's a, you know, fun fact.
That wasn't even me in that video.
That's so funny.
Everyone bought it, you know, when I put the video out.
They were like, oh my god, look at him.
He's so handsome.
It's like, damn, I wish that was me.
But it wasn't.
Full eclipse and isolate.
Okay.
Are you there?
What if we used the whole hotbar telepathy?
Last time I used the entire hotbar.
I used one, two, three, four, five, six...
Seven?
No.
CRV.
What do you mean?
I even put special effort into doing that last time.
Okay, but listen.
Hear me out.
I think my way of doing it is actually superior to your way.
Because what are you suggesting?
Okay, now I'm building something, so I'm gonna put stuff on...
The last five...
Slots in my heartbar?
What about all the other stuff you usually use there?
What about your food?
I think...
My way of doing it is superior.
And I will die on that hill.
Speaking of hills...
Here's another hill I'm willing to die on.
Nah, I'm not gonna say that now.
It's too depressing.
I'm not gonna...
Nah, we'll wait with that.
Maybe I'll feel it later.
Yeah, no backseating.
You can't do...
Yeah, dying sucks, man.
I'm willing to die on that hill, you know?
No, I'm not!
Because I want...
Dying sucks.
I don't want to do that.
10 stream streak.
Nice one.
Wait, who has the longest stream streak right now?
Is there a way for me to see that?
That's actually kind of interesting stats.
Manual blinking...
Noooo, stop!
Now I'm doing it manually.
Why would you say that?
And then this guy says the game.
Uh...
You know.
Oh, man.
You can see the Eclipse and the Percy.
It's pretty well from the hill.
Before you die, though.
Oh!
Good point!
What about the eye, though?
I want to see that.
The one on...
Oh god, what is it?
Aldani?
That's what I want to see before I die.
In real life.
I want to see the eye of Aldani.
You are now processing food.
No, that's not...
That doesn't...
Doesn't even make sense.
Manual bowel movement.
You can use buttons and plate to stop water or lava for fan.
Thank you, but you shouldn't tell me that.
I actually fell for it, man.
I'm usually good at spotting these, but I actually just...
I just read that.
And you know what was funny?
I already forgot.
I'm not even kidding.
No, wait.
You said something about fans and...
Plates.
Something about plates and fans.
Don't tell me how to play the game.
It's just more fun for me to figure out on my own, you know?
Even if it's painful for you guys.
You have to...
Listen, I understand that you guys want me to experience everything there is.
And I've said this before, you know?
But the best way you can do that is to not say anything because...
I'm gonna get more enjoyment out of it, you know?
Now...
That you said that...
It's not gonna be as cool when I do it, right?
The best feeling ever...
Is to figure something out.
And be like, whoa!
You know?
But maybe that's just me.
Maybe I'm alone in that.
You start the game, bro.
Ah, that's another five minutes until we start.
You should know by now.
By the way, someone mentioned...
That there's a mod for Minecraft where you can put in...
Like a little tablet.
Like a handheld one.
And you can see Twitch chat on it.
I think that would be fun.
To do.
You know?
Maybe have the Twitch chat in my house on a wall.
And I go there sometimes and look at it.
Wouldn't that be hilarious?
Like a quick glance and then look away?
Or something?
I think that could be so funny.
When do we start the capitalism to fuel the industrialization?
Uh...
Well, we don't need that.
Because I collect and do everything myself.
I don't need to hire people and, you know, have a whole economy going.
But you would have to Craig it.
That's even better, dude!
That sounds funny as hell.
You know?
You crank it up slowly.
And then the image comes in.
It's like...
Static at first.
You know?
There's snow on the screen.
And then I crank it.
And slowly the chat appears.
And then after a while, you know, it runs out of battery again.
And the chat disappears.
That would be so funny.
Dude, I'm gonna do that for next time.
Hold on.
Let me write that down.
That is freaking fantastic.
What a great suggestion.
Chat on tablet that needs cranking.
That is wonderful.
When do we put those orphans to work?
Ah, I can't do the voice.
You know the one from Lemmy?
When do we plan to start?
Man, I watched a lot of Lemmy clips lately.
Again, I get recommended Lemmy clips all the time on my YouTube.
By the way, I just want to say this.
I've been reading some YouTube comments, you know?
And I've noticed that there's a lot of negativity lately.
Like, people are just angry.
And they're upset.
At various things.
The way I play.
Or the mods I'm using.
Or this or that.
And I have one thing to say to you.
I don't care.
Stay mad.
I'm gonna have my fun.
I don't care.
What you think.
I play it the way I play it.
And you know what?
I'm gonna enjoy it.
To the full.
You can't make me mad.
You can't get to me.
So what?
I don't use my whole hot bar.
Or this or that.
Why are you spending all this energy being this angry on the internet?
Just let me play some Minecraft.
Let me do silly things.
I'll have fun, you know?
Life is too short to be angry all the time.
About this or that.
Come on.
Am I right?
Angry people everywhere on the internet.
Especially on social media these days.
You know, a new trailer comes out.
I saw this, by the way.
So there was a trailer for the Odyssey, right?
And I saw the trailer.
And I thought, damn, that's cool, man!
Then I read the comments.
Everyone's shitting on it.
The movie is not even out.
Or this was back then.
What are these actors?
How dare it not stay true to the Greek...
Whatever the fuck, you know?
Why is it in IMAX?
Someone said that too, like...
Dude!
It's a movie!
Calm down!
You know?
It's insane how much anger there is.
And I feel like some of that has been spreading to my channel as well.
No doubt because of the influx of new people, but still.
Let's just not be as angry, okay?
Let's just take it easy and enjoy life.
Life is hard enough as it is, you know?
Okay.
With that out of the way...
That was, by the way, the hill I was willing to die on before that I didn't mention.
But this was it.
Yeah, I'm a guru now.
I give life advice.
You can come to my lectures.
I'm gonna be up there, you know?
I'm gonna wear a tight white shirt.
I'm gonna have a little flash card and fancy glasses and a little mic that goes from my ear to my mouth.
Yep.
Subscribe.
Wait, is the game even open?
Oh my god!
I thought I launched the game.
No, it is... no, it crashed?
What happened?
I think it crashed.
By the way, I made a little mod for Minecraft.
Something very simple that I said I would do last time.
Which is...
There's now creative music in Survival.
But there's also the new music in Survival that came with the later patches.
So everything is now in here.
And not only that, but something I've been annoyed with for a very long time, ever since I started Minecraft, is that...
The mastering on these tracks is totally off.
In fact, I found out there's a 48 decibel difference between perceived loudness on these tracks.
So everything has been normalized, without affecting the dynamic range on any of the single tracks.
So no more, oh, this is now too loud, I gotta turn it down.
Oh, this is too low, I gotta turn it up, you know?
Fixed.
So now we get to listen to all the tracks.
Isn't that great?
Okay, enough yapping.
Let's play some games.
Larger than Earth.
Look at this.
Oh!
Ah, there we go.
It needed a clap.
The snapping with the fingers doesn't work anymore.
The clap is what's needed here.
Okay, man.
21 mods installed.
I also added something very lewd this time around.
You'll find out.
It's gonna be great.
Hopefully it won't get banned.
By the way, um...
No, I'm not gonna tell you.
I was about to tell you a fun story, but I decided against it.
Why am I...
Oh, I was testing a bunch of stuff.
That's why my inventory is full of random crap.
Let's just fix that.
Gimme that.
Stone two.
Now, why did I make a stone pressure plate?
Probably just to test whether or not I discovered something new with that.
I think that's redstone.
I would argue.
Guys, the big thing.
We have discovered...
Wait, what?
Oh, it's over here.
We have discovered...
Train track!
We are making trains today.
Choo-choo...
Tommy Lee Jones with a smiley face or whatever.
You know that...
Kindergarten...
You know, animated...
Show on...
TV?
I don't know if I forgot...
Tommy the...
Tank or whatever.
Train track!
We need stone slabs.
Actually, any slab seems to work.
Do I have any already?
I got a couple.
Times three.
Oh, I also need to make a sequence thingy here.
So, train...
I'm gonna do this immediately, by the way, because I am too hyped about trains.
And we need nuggets.
So, two deployers and...
A smasher.
I may have it.
Oh.
One, two.
Also, by the way...
Oh my god, there's a frog in my mouth.
So, it says depots.
But...
I think we can just use a...
Conveyor belt.
And it'll work just fine.
What is that sound?
People wanna give me random keys.
Dude, that's like...
One thing.
Nah, I don't even wanna get into that.
That's...
That's just a lot of spam, let's just say that.
Sink nuggets, iron nuggets.
I actually have a lot of those.
I just got a bunch.
We need one press.
Don't think I have that.
I mean, I have one outside, but...
Other than that...
Don't think so.
Block of iron, shaft, and casing.
Casing...
Oh my god, I have so many casings!
Look at that!
Should we fix the floor, first thing?
Wait.
Because I know I've been putting that off for a while.
I need to see here.
Pretty sure I have a lot of andesite thingies.
Ah, but the problem is they're not gonna come out unless there's room.
So I can't actually do that.
That's fine.
I'll just wait.
Yeah.
It's no problem.
We can make that manually.
At some point.
By the way, today I'm not even gonna use any hotbar slots.
Also, I will not use any keybinds.
I will only scroll with my mouse.
In fact, I'm gonna bring out a touchpad as well instead of a mouse.
Here.
Let's see if I can...
Oh my god, that's so hard to hit.
Oh.
And now, click.
Yeah, click.
This is the new reality, guys.
Get ready.
Just kidding.
There's no touchpad.
It's my mouse.
I'm just acting.
We need a press, dammit!
We need to make this...
and turn it into...
that.
A shaft!
I think I should have brought some from where I was just now.
I failed miserably.
No.
Not that.
Wait, there must be another way to make it.
No, it's an andesite.
Ah, that's so annoying!
Okay, fine.
I'll go back.
No problem.
Cheers.
I can't wait to hear the creative music!
It's gonna be good.
I think it was...
Iron?
No, sink.
Definitely sink.
And andesite, andesite, we have...
Oh, we don't even have that!
Oh, wait, no...
No...
I don't have any andesite?
Dude, what a shitty problem to have!
I just need a little bit...
Okay, wait, we have shafts.
Everything's fine.
Calm down!
It's okay.
The day is saved.
I can't believe shafts are so hard to craft.
But I seem to remember there being a different way to craft shafts.
Shaft.
Now.
Press.
Look at that!
Kinetic stress impact is high.
I wonder what that is even...
Meant to mean.
Oh!
It probably means that in the system of, you know...
Interconnected machines.
It simply means that this one contributes a lot to the stress factor.
That's it.
So it's gonna break sooner, you know?
Or stop working sooner.
That's all that means.
Great!
So we have these two and that one.
Then we have belts back there, and...
Other than that...
I think we're done, really.
Maybe some more slaps?
I mean...
We probably need a lot, right?
Let's see.
Train track.
Yeah, so we put a slab in and some nuggets.
And we get that.
Man, this is gonna run for a while.
Is this gonna produce one of these?
And how big is that gonna be?
This is a question I have now.
Let's find out, shall we?
I think we have everything we need.
Alright.
And cheers.
Oh, by the way, I also made it.
So that the tracks play a little more often.
Not that much more often, but you know, there's a larger randomized factor to it.
So just so we can have a bit more music.
Because I want to hear the new tracks, right?
Okay, so I think we should just expand this factory.
So this is the first part of the factory.
This produces and the side casings.
And then we can have a separate area over here, maybe?
Where we produce train tracks.
It's going to be a little messy at the end.
But you know what?
That's part of the charm.
That's, uh...
By design.
Let's grab some belts.
And we only need like...
Five, maybe.
Don't need that much.
And we have shafts, great.
The question is...
I may have to siphon some of this energy we have here for this.
Would be a good idea.
This one is close to being overstressed.
So we take from...
We want to take from here...
No, let's take from here because it's already fast.
Like that.
And let's put one...
Over here.
But that's spinning that way.
Do we like that?
Maybe I hate that actually.
Hmm.
Well, it only needs three slots, right?
Lock it!
Let's go!
Look at that!
And now...
Uh...
I guess I'll use...
No!
Mistake.
What should I use?
So we need two deployers and a hammer.
Can I really not...
Oh!
Sick!
You can do that!
You need to put a block up here first!
Okay, well...
In that case...
Also, isn't this belt kind of fast?
It doesn't need to be that fast, right?
Maybe it's actually bad when you have a fast belt.
I'm not sure.
Oh, that's so nice.
Now we need sink.
Half and half.
There you go.
Then we should have a little chest at the end too.
Of course I don't have that.
Let's make one.
Chest.
Let's have...
Actually, I need two of them.
I need one at the end and one at front.
Ah, but wait a sec.
Needs to be elevated a tiny bit.
This is the train track fabricator.
TTF.
Now we need the little tunnel thingies.
And funnels.
I mean, not tunnels.
There we go.
Look at that.
Now in here we are going to put slabs.
And that should just work.
Oh, we need to connect this, obviously, before we start.
There's no power yet.
The best way to do that is to, I guess, maybe use some wheels.
I don't have any.
Gears.
No, cogs.
Ah, I don't want to use all my shafts.
Let's take three.
What's the best way to do...
I guess just...
Like that, and then we connect one of these.
That's the easiest way to do it.
But I need to make a couple more.
Ah, crap.
I need one more.
That's my last.
Wonderful!
Okay, here we go.
Also, this is just floating in the air.
That's unnatural.
So let's fix that.
Oh!
No.
Yeah.
And now...
Look at this!
Look at this little train maker right here, dude!
Are you ready?
Here we... Oh!
I can't open that.
But you know what, guys?
That's why we have slabs!
That's so pretty, actually.
Take a picture.
That's one for the memory books.
Okay.
Here we go!
Wait, why is this hand empty?
It appears this deployer contains excess items that need to be extracted.
Use a hopper funnel or other means to free it from its overflow.
Say what now?
Exquisite me?
Wait, hold on.
What's wrong?
Wait, wait, wait.
Take this out.
Oh, shit.
Yeah, why is this one not, uh...
Pointing?
Contains excess items.
Okay, I guess I'll use a hopper?
Or a funnel?
But I don't understand.
Hold on.
Yeah, there it is!
Okay, that doesn't...
I'm not gonna say it, but it feels a little...
You know?
Yeah, look at the hands!
The hands are moving.
Half and half.
There you go.
There we go.
Now it should work.
Bup!
Oh, yeah!
Hi!
It's actually just working!
Cheers!
Oh, that is sexy to look at.
Look!
And so compact!
Very nice!
And look!
It puts one of them on.
And then the other, so there's two?
Actually, no.
It puts one on.
Oh, that seems weird.
There should be two on this one.
And then this attaches them.
But still, uh...
Oh, wait!
It's making a lot at a time!
Oh, no, it's not.
It's one at a time.
Oh, let's see!
Oh, that looks so good!
A new type of rail designed for train contraptions.
Wow, that looks good.
Okay.
To place rows of track in bulk.
Dude, I hope I can do this old thing.
Where two people are on it, you know, and they go up and down, up and down to go down.
But instead of up and down, we do round and round with a crank.
Think of Charlie Chaplin, right?
To place rows of track in bulk.
Click on an existing track.
Oh, really?
So we can drag it?
And place or select a second track.
Oh, nice!
Can we turn it as well, though?
Must be able to.
That's beautiful!
Oh my god, it's like... round!
Tracks can also be placed as turns or slopes.
Tell me it's a smooth slope.
It's gotta be.
When connecting tracks, we'll try to make each turn equally sized.
Right.
Makes sense.
This looks so incredibly good.
Holding the sprint key while...
connecting?
That's not sprint.
That's crouch.
Get it right.
We'll create the longest fitting bend instead.
Okay.
Oh, here we go.
Oh my god, look at these holders.
Oh, it's smooth.
Materials in the offhand will be paved under tracks automatically.
Huh?
Okay, that's weird.
Okay.
The girders.
Tracks and the nether?
No.
We can go through?
We'll attempt to create a paired track on the other side.
Oh, man!
The trains on this track are now able to travel across dimensions.
That is amazing.
Oh, hell yeah.
Traversing unloaded...
chunks.
I read that as something else at first.
Track stay functional outside of loaded chunks.
Oh, actually, I know what that is.
Uh, so a chunk is like 16 by 16 or something.
It's where you spawn or something, right?
And then outside of that, if it's not loaded, it means it's not simulated either, I guess.
Wait, I need to read that again?
Trains will travel through inactive sections of the world without issue.
Okay.
Wait, so...
You're saying it's simulated even though it's not.
So this is, you know, overriding the simulation...
parameter.
It will still stop at stations or RET signals.
Whoa!
Wait, we can have signals?
However, drills and other onboard machines will not operate.
Ah, okay.
Okay.
Got it.
Of course you can put a drill on it, but...
Yeah.
Oh my god, it looks so good!
Once near a player, the train will reappear.
Okay.
So it is just simulated, but it's not like visually simulated, but it doesn't matter because you can't see it anyway, right?
Makes sense, dude!
Let me see, is it...
Oh my god.
Yo, wait, wait, this is gonna cost a lot.
This is not, uh...
cheap.
Wait a sec.
This is gonna be an expensive affair!
Wait, why are these purple?
Ah!
That's why.
I still had it in...
I see, I see, I see.
Okay.
Well, yeah.
You can't point anymore right now.
You got no nuggets left.
We need to make more train tracks.
But we also have to remember that...
Uh...
We need a train!
We can't just have tracks!
Um...
Let's get over here.
Now we do full and full.
Notice how I'm using two slots here.
See that?
See, then you have to go back and put it back, you know, it's...
My way superior.
Hmm.
Wait, uh...
I must have unlocked more, now that I did this.
I didn't pay attention to the top right.
Train.
Uh...
Signal?
Didn't it say something about signal...
Uh...
Station, maybe?
Train...
What else is related to trains?
There must be something.
Also, let me wear these goggles.
Finally.
Uh...
Put this back.
Oh, that's so nice!
You get to see how many are in there!
Okay, the goggles are amazing.
Oh, we ran out of slabs.
Mayday.
Put them in.
Okay, we make a lot of these now.
This is actually no problem.
Okay, I need to see this again, though.
Because...
How do I make a train?
So this looks like...
Okay, we don't know what that is.
Or that.
Subject of this scene.
Okay.
Show me the big one you had in this next one.
That one.
I mean, I guess it's just...
You need some kind of source of power, right?
Well, then again, if there's electricity and we can...
You know, go through the tracks...
I don't know.
These look like levers.
Oh, this is like a control panel.
I have one of these, actually.
But this looks like a...
Not an andesite version, but the other one.
The brass version.
The wheels, though, I...
Look very metal-y, right?
So...
I mean, we should just keep crafting metals.
Last time we unlocked so many things just by crafting...
Random stuff, you know?
So it makes sense.
Honeyed apple.
I wonder what that's good for.
Maybe it's like really good to eat.
Better than a steak, maybe.
I also want to make this.
That's just three of these in a row.
That seems easy enough.
Transmitter.
I made that already.
Stock link.
Yeah, we should make stuff like this.
Oh!
There's also stuff we can make now.
With the crafter thingy.
That I want to do today as well.
Let's see if I can find it.
There was something we could make.
Doesn't this look like the thing that would be on a train?
Package...
I don't know what a frog port is.
I'm imagining a gate for frogs, but that doesn't make any sense, obviously.
Maybe it's a common English express...
Oh, maybe...
Oh!
Metal girder, maybe!
This looks train-y, doesn't it?
Nixie tube.
This one I've made already.
Iron sheets and andesite alloys.
Turntable.
That could also be related to trains.
Then again, maybe I should just make wheels and it'll give me inspiration to make other wheels, you know?
This thing is nuts.
Physics assembler.
Okay.
How many did I make?
I have almost two stacks of this.
We should have a train station next to our home.
Dude, maybe the train goes into our factory.
Like, inside of it.
And...
Oh my god, wait.
Can we somehow make logistical transports of goods?
Because let's say I'm out mining somewhere, you know?
And I have some sort of system set up that fills the train with raw material.
And then the train transports it to my factory.
And it unloads it and it will allow craft things for me.
Doesn't that sound incredible?
Sounds really difficult though, but I think we can do it.
Um...
Propeller bearing.
I don't think I've made an andesite tunnel.
Okay, well...
Uh...
The train will have to wait a little bit, I think.
Until we craft some more stuff here.
Black tablecloth?
No, this is the one I made.
Not the, uh, the one with the levers.
Yeah.
You know what?
Let's just continue what we did last time.
And make a bunch of shit right now.
Like random stuff.
This is good though.
This is for the digging machine.
The belts, uh...
They can stay in here.
Put these back in here.
God, I gotta make more shafts.
Because this is just not enough.
But what I intend to do...
It ain't enough, Captain.
Okay.
So...
Let's make some stuff.
This is why I had this in my inventory.
I'm just gonna take a bunch.
See what else I could make.
Let's see where I was.
Hmm.
Oh, that felt...
Good!
Been a long time coming.
Let's do it again.
Jim.
Oh, yeah!
I can't get enough of Jim.
What do you want me to say?
Okay, unlock some more stuff there.
What?!
Oh!
Wait, I guess I can make sand out of...
Sandstone.
We can crush it.
Tough bricks.
Ah, this is not gonna do anything.
Maybe granite...
Polished granite?
No.
Look at all this new stuff.
Polished blackstone button.
That is so oddly specific, isn't it?
Wait, a mossy cobblestone wall?
Actually sounds pretty fire.
Let me see how that looks.
I'm imagining like the British countryside, you know?
How they have these funny walls.
Look at that, man!
That's beautiful!
Love it!
Very nice.
In fact, I wanna make more.
Let me just decorate a little bit with this.
But it's like incomplete, you know?
It's part of the charm.
Ah!
Dude, tell me this doesn't look incredible.
Oh, there's a tree growing in my path.
Can't have that.
Gotta maintain the land here a little bit.
Oh yeah?
Bring it on, I need level 30.
Come on.
Oh, it's so beautiful, it adds so much.
It adds like a whole new dimension.
Literally.
Height.
And it's nice.
Now, what did I not make?
This one.
I'm just gonna throw stuff out, I think.
That I don't want.
Oh!
I burned a lot of cobblestone accidentally.
That was a mistake.
Why didn't you get burned?
There you go.
Makes me feel better.
Okay.
Now what else have I not tried?
Andeside.
I guess azurene.
Calcite.
Maybe...
Granted, I have tried...
Andeside?
Maybe there's something out of andeside.
We should make here.
Andeside slab.
Polished andeside.
Oh!
I guess polished stairs and stuff.
Okay.
That's cool.
Let's see what else we can make.
What looks exotic?
Glowstone, maybe?
I think I made that one, actually.
This one!
Copper!
Great!
I did not make that yet.
See if I remember how this works.
Wait!
You need four?
Okay, fine.
Great.
Oh, it didn't do anything!
Oh, that's a bummer.
Yeah, see, now it doesn't belong in here anymore.
Now it's a construction.
And what about this azurene stuff?
Oh, it's...
Oh, azurene calcite.
Hmm.
Alright.
Doesn't seem to be anything there.
Let's make some redstone components.
This seems like a thing that could do a lot, right?
Oh, what about the crafter?
Dropper.
Dropper, crafting table.
I don't even think I have a dropper at this point.
I do.
Wow.
Crafting table.
Iron ingots and redstone.
CD-Ref.
Yeah, so...
This is the thing with the crafter, right?
I understand why there's another thing in create.
Even though this thing exists.
And it's because...
Some of the recipes require more slots than nine.
So I get that part.
I still don't understand how to use this...
Purely from vanilla, you know?
Like, how will I automatically put stuff in here?
Maybe with a hopper or something?
From each side?
I don't know.
That one's a bit of a mystery to me.
Maybe some bars?
Oh!
Look at that!
What is that?
It looked coppery.
Item drain.
Copper casing.
I got that.
I think.
No...
Do I?
I got it, I got it, I got it.
Oh, here we go!
Ponder it.
Item drains can extract fluids from items.
Okay.
Right click it to pour fluids from your health item into it.
When items are inserted from the side?
We can fill it?
Oh no!
Automatically emptied.
Oh, okay.
Yeah.
They roll across, emptying out their contained fluid.
Smart.
And you can of course, yeah, combine it with all of this.
Got it.
Pipe networks can now pull the fluid from the drain's internal buffer.
All right.
So it's just a way to empty your items, I guess.
If you have bottles or buckets.
That's kind of cool.
I dig it.
I do.
That's neat.
Let's put it in here.
I guess it's kind of...
Spout and... wait, hold on.
Couldn't I simply make a spout that spouts out water?
Into this item drain?
That is then being pumped up into the spout?
That spouts into the item drain?
And then goes up into the spout?
And then just keeps going?
It's like the infinite flow, trademark.
It's infinity flow.
But optimized.
I like it.
What else can I make?
Let's make an iron trapdoor.
Wait.
I think I've had this before.
In the other world?
This is the thing where I can empty all my items, right?
Immediately.
This is what happens when you just start crafting.
Item hatch.
Quickly solves your inventory clutter and makes it someone else's problem.
This will be used for my inevitable item filter.
Deposit your held item into the container it is placed on.
Sneak click to deposit everything except hotbar items.
Wonderful.
Very nice.
That's good.
Probably should make it.
I think I have a little bit of andesite somewhere.
I do need it.
Oh, I made slaps out of it all?
There's no way.
Stone.
I used it all.
Well!
It is what it is.
Let's make a pressure plate.
Nothing.
Did I ever do this?
I guess I did.
Turn it back.
Shears I've made.
Iron door I've not made.
Now I regret making it.
Okay, what else?
I'm trying to focus on making items that are not like directly create related.
Wait, how do I actually make bricks?
I forgot.
Oh wait, it's here, isn't it?
Oh, that's it.
Clay balls!
I got it.
Check this out!
We can even...
We cannot do it here.
Let's see what that produces.
In fact, maybe I really should be looking at this inventory a bit more.
Nether brick seems kinda important too.
Maybe let's do that as well.
Nether.
Let's just bring one for now.
Okay, so getting the brick didn't do anything.
But we did need more than one brick to make things happen.
Okay?
Just the...
I can just cook that I guess.
The funny thing is...
Oh, stop climbing.
This is a blaster.
And this recipe is not in here.
So I don't think I can actually blast it outside.
I can only smoke it, but this is not smoking.
This is just...
Furnacing.
So this may not be able...
I probably can't do this with the blaster outside.
Maybe there's another way of doing it, where you don't smoke and you don't blast, but you do something in between.
Now we have four bricks.
Break wall.
See, this is what I'm imagining for the factory.
Doesn't that look very factory?
I think that's very factory.
This one seems important.
Two stone brick slaps.
I can make it.
Huh?
Something about the fan.
Chiseled.
Oh!
I can infest it.
With the blue fire.
I don't know why...
I mean, I guess I'll have to try it.
Don't knock it till you try it, right?
But still.
This is painfully slow.
I feel like this can be done better.
Yeah, let's not think about that right now.
Iron stuff.
I would say that belongs in construction.
Redstone.
Let me see what else we got.
I forgot where I was.
Oh, there's not even that much here.
Hold on, did I click on it?
I did.
Okay, so...
Cut sandstone.
What does that even mean?
Four sandstones.
We can try that.
So we make sandstone first.
Cut sandstone.
Nice.
I mean, it's more.
Don't think I've made this.
We need glass and iron nuggets.
Glass...
And nukes.
It's probably gonna look amazing.
Maybe not here.
Let's put it.
Hey, you know what?
I like it.
We have a little corner window here.
Sweet.
Gym.
The chain I already made.
I guess we can try...
Yeah, tinted glass.
Make all of that.
Oh, look at that!
What is that?
There it is.
Laser sensor.
Oh, I thought I had that already.
I have something like this, I guess.
Huh, alright.
Nice.
Maybe a kelp...
Wait, does that...
I thought it said super dried kelp block.
I have kelp.
Nope, I don't.
Not enough at least.
I don't have any pointed dripstone.
Dude, are you seeing this little graphical error that I'm seeing on this stair?
Look at it.
You see the little pixels there.
Am I seeing this?
Like, this game is literally unplayable.
Let's make a post box.
I need a barrel.
This.
And...
Slap.
Ah, I need more.
Turn this into...
That.
I guess we can just make...
Oh, we need an alloy for that?
I don't... I can't make it.
I don't have an alloy.
Shit.
We can't make that either.
That's crazy.
This one I already made, I think?
No, it was these ones I made.
Let's make it.
Didn't do anything.
Whatever.
Wait!
Concrete powder!
Yo!
Sand and gravel...
Oh, this may be big!
Is there anything more...
Industrial than concrete?
Oh, I guess I would have to mill it to get sand back.
I'm gonna go get some sand.
Fuck it.
Operation get sand.
Engage.
We can also get some kelp while we're here.
Oh, you're lucky, you bastard.
Let me get some sand.
Bum, bum, bum, bum.
Bum, bum, bum, bum, bum.
Bum, bum, bum, bum, bum, bum.
Isn't that beautiful?
You think I could become a singer?
If Lemmy can get famous with his wrong way down a one-way street...
I mean...
I think I could...
Do anything.
You know?
Bum, bum, bum.
Oh, I mistimed it!
Oh my god, I'm an idiot.
I messed it up.
I like how I went here earlier to get like a million kelp for the belts.
And I've used 5% of all the belts I made.
You know?
I think it's kind of funny.
Oh shit, we're dying.
Yeah!
Crap cake!
Should've brought a boat.
Yeah, this is painful.
Then again, do I really need this much?
Probably not.
Oh!
The fuck was that?!
Did you hear that?!
It disappeared when I went up!
That was crazy!
Wait, he's eating the kelp!
Oh my god, I'm so fast!
Thank you!
Sun is going down.
Let's go.
What else can I make with this kelp?
I can only make...
Oh, it's dried kelp.
Right.
Uh...
Smoke it.
I need to make this though.
Gravel and sand.
Gravel.
I got it, dude!
Concrete!
Oh, do we need color though?
Can I not just make...
Plain concrete with no color?
The hell?
Uh...
No problem though, I got some dye.
Oh, come on!
There's gotta be more than that!
What?
Oh wait, uh...
This is the powder.
We make concrete now, and then we can do something with it.
White concrete!
Look at that!
Wait, we wash it?
Uh...
Okay.
I can do that.
No problem.
Uh...
That's not what I expected, but okay.
Let's sleep.
I'm gonna wash this powder now.
Uh...
Yeah, look at that!
Oh, the washing has begun!
Can I wash myself of my sins?
Do I become nice and clean?
Oh wait, did I pick it up before?
Shit, I made a mistake.
Just leave it there for now.
Uh...
Okay.
Wonder what else I can wash.
Let's check it.
Wash, wash, wash.
Bulk washing!
You can wash the windows to make them normal.
Can I wash my friend Peter to make him normal?
Hmm...
You wash gravel?
Oh, it's like finding gold, you know?
Magma block becomes obsid...
Okay.
That is like the ultimate way to get obsidian.
Sand becomes clay ball.
Whoa!
This is actually kinda dope.
Soul sand.
Makes nether quartz.
It should be done now.
Didn't trigger anything, unfortunately.
I am very upset.
Okay, well...
How does this look?
It is literally just white!
That is the most boring block of all time.
It's like hashtag FFFFFF.
Minus one F, I think.
That's how they did that.
Nah, I think it's a little off-white.
It's like maybe bone, you know?
And there's a watermark too.
There, there.
Is my stuff done?
It is done.
Make one of these.
Oh, here we go!
Look at that!
What?
What, what is that?
Hold on!
We unlocked something big just now!
Wait, elevator pulley?
Don't I have that already?
Monstrous tire?
A monstrously large all-terrain wheel.
Wait a minute.
I was about to make like an Akram ATW.
And then I realized.
Isn't there a vehicle that's actually called an ATV?
Maybe that's where it comes from.
Hose pulley.
Don't know what that means.
A pulley with water?
Or what?
Like a hose?
Don't understand.
Isn't there something else?
Oh, right.
Milk.
We can make a pipe with milk.
Wait a second.
Can I, can I make a system where we automatically milk the cows?
I'm thinking via pipes.
You know?
Right, okay.
There was something else.
Grass?
Wait, grass block?
Haha!
I can water it with the spout and it becomes green.
That, and yeah, you can fill the bottle.
It makes sense.
And fill them, I guess.
Uncraftable potion?
Right.
You can put whatever you want in there.
Got it.
Oh!
This is what I need!
I don't know how to get this.
This is probably gonna unlock some crazy shit.
Sand.
Okay, well, I'm pretty sure I saw something else.
Not sure where that is.
Anyway.
Making progress here.
Let's keep making things.
What have I not made?
I think all of this has been made.
Oh, the post box!
But I still need andesite alloy.
I don't have that right now.
We can make a nameplate.
Ah, it requires alloy.
I really do need alloys for a lot.
Diorite is heavy.
Oh!
I can see this because I have the glasses on.
That's why these tooltips are there.
I may not actually have had this.
Magma block.
Wait a sec!
I don't think I've had that!
Four magma creams.
I actually have that, I think.
Seems like an awful waste of it.
Ah, I'm not gonna waste it.
Also, give me these.
I should probably cook the other ones too.
The dried kelp block is super heavy.
Also, I don't know what that unit is.
Kilo...
Puckram?
I don't know.
KG makes sense to me.
KPG?
Kilo...
Prep...
Ponder...
Picture...
I don't know.
I think they're made up units.
In fact, I think this game is made up.
I know.
I'm possessed by some radical notions.
Another brick.
Ah, you are actually construction real.
No, you're not.
You're smelting.
Kelp, you go in here.
Ah, I really wanna put this in there.
Let me just do another check here.
Train...
That's really everything I see when I do train.
That's insane.
Okay.
It's time for achievements.
Create simulated.
Let's see.
You spin me right around.
Assemble a simulated contraption using a swivel bearing.
I don't have that, I don't think.
Let me see.
I think I can make it though.
No, I can't.
Maybe it's with...
I don't know how to spell it.
Okay, whatever.
Don't know what a swivel bearing is.
Something that swivels?
Rewind time?
Watch a torsion spring unwind to its original position.
Aww.
I thought for a second we can make a time machine.
Go back to the 60's.
The real golden era.
Just kidding.
Place in power a redstone magnet.
Huh!
A magnet!
That I don't have.
Successfully align and connect two docking connectors.
This sounds like something that could be used with a train.
You know, train cars can be docked together.
Either that or we do the interstellar docking scene.
Place in power a portable engine.
Now this sounds incredible.
Craft a plunger launcher.
Alright.
Connect a rope connector or rope spool.
Wait, obtain and place a navigation table to point you in the right direction!
That sounds incredible!
Incredible!
But I can't make it.
Hmm.
Well, there's nothing really here that's gonna...
You know, tell me anything about trains it seems like.
Maybe that's part of this.
Program a mechanical arm with ten or more output locations.
Now this sounds great!
Not sure how to make it though.
Also this one.
Operate a pair of crushing wheels at maximum speed.
Use your wrench on a pipe that contains a fluid.
Why?
What does that do?
Should we try that?
Now I'm curious.
It's probably just gonna rotate it and I'm gonna get wet.
That's my prediction for that.
And that's the extent of it.
Either that or a little, uh...
Little pajama comes out, you know?
Um, here.
Flow discovery!
Hey!
That's beautiful.
That's not so beautiful.
Now I just got some free water.
Thanks!
Yeah, you can make them kinda cool looking.
Oh, I didn't mean to do that.
Put it back.
I wanna make this cool looking.
Hey, look!
Very nice.
I can probably...
affect lots of things with this, you know?
Oops!
Didn't mean to do that.
We got the achievement.
Use a portable storage interface to take or insert items into a contraption.
Now, this one sounds like it could be very useful.
It's also very early in the discovery tree here.
Still haven't assembled a windmill!
I think I have that one, actually.
Portable storage interface.
It sounds like one of those things that...
could be massively useful when I finally get it.
And I've yet to make it for some reason.
This could change my life.
I will find it without mousing over.
I'll show you.
It is that one.
Let's see it.
Hmm.
Right.
That is indeed tricky.
But this component can interact with storage without the need to stop it.
Ooh!
Right.
Place a second one with a gap of one or two blocks in between.
Oh!
Whenever they pass by each other, they will engage in a connection.
While engaged, the stationary interface will represent all inventories on the contraption.
Whoa!
So, okay.
Both chests.
Items can now be inserted.
Oh!
That's actually super cool.
I'm trying to think how I can use this with my digging machine, but I can't really.
At least not as easily.
This is like a machine that rotates.
In fact, maybe I should make a rotating machine.
Or extract it, yeah.
This is probably super essential for my plan of transporting goods with the train automatically from one place to another.
And then using those materials in the assembly line.
Oh, what is this?
What happened there?
Redstone power will prevent the stationary interface from engaging.
Ah, okay.
Must be a common thing.
What is the point of this?
Oh, it's like a crane, I guess?
It's like a little thing that picks up items, goes somewhere else, delivers it.
It's just a different way of doing it.
Neat.
Now, the mechanical bearing.
I feel like this is a big deal.
Mechanical bearings attached to the block in front of them.
Upon receiving rotational force, it will assemble it into a rotating contraption.
Yeah.
Well, there's more to this, right?
When stopped, the bearing will place the structure at the nearest grid-aligned angle.
Okay, but I don't understand what you would use this for.
Modified.
Okay, hold on.
What's this?
Traption controls.
Oh my god, see this?
Oh no, I closed it.
I didn't mean to!
Damn it!
Where was it?
Here.
I need this!
This is a harvester.
Look at that!
Looks like one of those I had as a child when I was mowing the lawn.
The manual ones, you know?
We should make this!
Let's make an automated harvester, boy!
But I don't know what it's...
It's actually just called a harvester, maybe.
Oh!
Mechanical harvester.
I haven't even made it yet.
Oh, alloys!
Okay, you know what?
It's time.
Let's go get some goddamn alloy before I lose my mind.
I'm not even gonna bring a shield, because this is a quick in and out adventure.
20 minutes tops.
Maybe more like 5 minutes tops.
Actually, we just need andesite.
Let's go...
Ah, let's go down here.
This may be a mistake.
I'm not sure.
HALA!
Oh!
Ooh!
That was a little risky, man!
That jump was crazy.
What am I smoking?
I could have died.
That was way too close.
I'll take that.
Thank you.
I think I went too deep, maybe.
For andesite.
Shit.
Let's go back up.
Just a bit.
I mean, I'll pick this up on the way.
Bum bum bum bum bum.
Wait, I forgot what andesite looks like.
I'll know it when I see it.
Oh, we got a boy over there.
There.
I think.
Oh, here it is!
We got it right here!
That's andesite, baby.
That's not andesite.
Is he coming over here?
He's not.
Oh, why did I do this?
Mistakes were made.
That should do it!
I am gonna use the elevator.
Get back up.
Take me up!
Hey, look!
Isn't that pretty?
Let's put a little light here.
Yeah!
Dumbass!
He died!
Wonderful.
I got what I need.
I even have nuggets.
And now we can make a bunch of other stuff that I wanted to make since I now have alloys.
That's fantastic.
Alloy!
Bop, bop, bop, bop, bop, bop.
Bop, bop, bop, bop, bop.
Fourteen is nice.
Harvest.
Requires sheets.
Which I don't have!
Damn.
But maybe there's some on the presser.
There is!
Oh my god!
That's incredible.
Here we go!
Harvester!
Fuck!
We need an andesite casing.
Show it to me.
Just one.
Harvest.
Ooh, let's see.
Three of them.
Whenever harvesters are moved as part of an animated contraption, they're gonna harvest.
And reset any nature crops on their way.
Wait, reset them?!
For free?!
Inventories attached to the contraption will pick up their drops automatically.
But what about the seeds?
Oh, I guess they pick up the seeds.
You know, and then they put them down automatically.
Right, they're not spawning them out of thin air.
Okay.
Well, that's super simple.
Hello.
That's easy.
Easiest farm of my life, in fact.
We will be relocating this farm.
You have done me good.
But it's time to stop.
No more.
This farm will be epic.
Dude, let's put a farm on the roof!
It's genius!
That's why I have greenery!
Look at this!
Oh, actually, it's too small.
Let's not put it on the roof.
I changed my mind.
Let's have it out here, or something.
Maybe here near the water.
I thought I had more space on the roof.
Oh!
Reaction times of a G-O-D, dude!
Wow!
Can't come and tell me I'm not a gamer after that.
That was actually wonderful.
I could have lost everything just now.
All my experience.
But I kept my cool.
And I came out unscathed.
Put it in.
Let's see this.
So, for the thingy, I think we need a little bearing or something.
Let me see.
That's a mechanical bearing!
Linear chassis!
I'm just gonna go ahead and use the linear chassis like they tell me to.
What you gonna do about it?
I got it somewhere.
There.
Not sure...
I forgot about the secondary one.
Locks and...
Oh, not alloys!
Please don't.
Oh, I got 17.
That should be good enough.
So watch this.
I'm gonna put it right over here.
Oh, I probably need a hole for that.
And I'm also thinking we should probably use...
some rotation.
It's not gonna rotate on its own.
I guess.
Maybe we also need glue?
Not entirely sure.
Hmm.
Now I'm thinking maybe I should put it out here.
Since I have rotation anyway.
But this is all temporary, isn't it?
We don't like what that is right now.
It kinda sucks.
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
Hold on.
Ideas are forming in my head.
I feel it.
Oh yeah, it's in there.
The idea is there.
It has developed.
We are putting a...
rotisserie farm on the roof.
Right here.
Why?
Let me answer.
I'm glad you asked.
It's because it doesn't matter how big the farm is.
We are gonna automate everything.
Which means everything that is being picked up by the machine is going to go down straight into a chest below the roof!
It's incredible.
What a breakthrough.
I did like the idea behind the green roof though.
But now it'll serve a greater purpose.
And I think we'll need one of those portable storage containers for this too.
So while it rotates, it's gonna blup, blup, blup, deposit, and then it's gonna keep rotating and then blup, blup, blup, and then it keeps going.
I think it's wonderful.
Okay.
Now.
What's a good spot?
Let me see.
Probably long here.
Where are we rotating anyway?
Aha!
Look at...
It's almost too good to be true.
It is unbelievable.
One, two, three...
Yep, that's good.
That's good.
Now to remember how this works...
I gotta see it again.
So you put the mechanical bearing down.
And...
Okay, that's gonna rotate.
Yep.
Okay.
Got it, got it.
You...
Got it.
Easy enough.
I'm just gonna put this here for now.
Mechanical bearing.
Oh, I don't have it with me.
Wait!
Oh my god.
Even better idea.
You thinking what I'm thinking, partner?
You thinking what I'm thinking.
I know you are.
Yeah.
Yep.
Yep, definitely.
We're doing that.
I will take the windmill...
And use its power directly!
Hold on, I can probably use my wrench.
Oh, it's much easier!
Look!
Done.
And then we're gonna re...
You know?
Out here again.
Now to remember how the windmill works.
So this is the windmill, right here.
Um...
Windmill bearing.
Boom!
Shit!
Try it again.
There we go.
And then I think it was this.
And then we did it like that.
And I did it like this.
I did it like that.
I did it like this.
And now...
We go up.
Now I kinda wanna try and make the...
You know, the old school windmill that is the other way.
But uh...
Nah!
I like this design.
I think it's cool.
Cool.
Maybe we'll have another windmill later.
Somewhere else.
There's also not room up here, you know, it's... No!
Gimme!
In fact, I'll make this windmill massive.
Oh, wait a sec!
We have a problem!
This is an issue.
Whoops.
This cannot be here.
We have to go a little further up.
In fact, I'll probably do this.
Look at that!
And now... Wait!
I think it needs to be a linear chassis.
Oh.
Really?
That made me unlock new things.
Wait, hold on.
Emergency ponder.
It's going up there.
Does it matter?
Maybe it doesn't matter.
Alright.
I mean, let's start small, I guess.
Bro, I gotta see this again.
Okay, so they... Okay, I see.
Got it.
It's connected.
This should work.
Oh, we need more sales.
In fact, let's make it even higher.
It's temporary.
It'll be better.
Four left.
Let's do up here.
Two.
Come on.
And four.
Yeah.
Now.
You ready?
Here we go.
Wait, what the f... Wait, what is happening?
Stop that!
Okay, first off, it's rotating the wrong way.
But I can just fix that by putting this on the other side.
There we go.
Now.
For some reason... Oh, I know.
I know why.
Here we go.
Shit.
No.
Stop.
Do I need an empty hand?
Okay.
Oh my god, yes.
It's working.
Not only that, we're gonna use this rotational energy down below as well.
Multi-purpose function.
MPF.
Because look.
See the rod?
It's spinning!
Gimme... I have one shaft left.
It's ordained.
Wonderful!
Now we connect it with a...
Gearbox.
This is so incredibly smart!
I actually can't believe it.
How do I make it?
Cockwheels and casings.
Uh...
Cockwheels...
Oh, they need shafts!
No!
I don't have any!
There's gotta be some back here.
This is like the ultimate blue ball.
Um...
Show me.
Yes!
I got one!
Beautiful!
That's all I needed.
Did you see that, parkour?
Get ready for greatness.
Yes.
And look at that!
It's all connected again!
Oh my god.
You can't tell me this ain't beautiful!
Not only that...
We're gonna make it better.
Maybe we will do some gear reductions in here.
Hmm.
Oh my god.
Oh, I'm so excited, dude.
Oh, let's go make a farm!
I need my hole.
Hole time.
Oh, we need seats.
We have seats.
Seats are good.
I can't wait to see this.
So, it's going along...
I wonder if it takes that one, too.
Wait, we need water!
I didn't think of this.
Maybe I can spout it?
We put a spout onto it as well.
Or...
Wait.
I don't know.
We need water.
I got water.
Maybe we have like a...
What do you think?
Every second one, you know, it's...
Hey, actually!
Hold on.
So, water goes four across, right?
So, we should...
If it doesn't take this...
Then it makes sense to put water here.
Oops.
This is awfully close to filling my house with water.
But, you know...
Bear with me.
We need to test with bone meal.
I need to see if it takes the edges.
Will it take the edge off or not?
Bone meal.
We should have a ladder inside to get up here quick.
Oh my god, look.
Oh!
It takes the edge!
Okay, okay.
It takes the edge.
Then we should probably not do this.
Maybe have the water somewhere else.
I mean, I could put it in here, but I'm planning to put more of these, you know?
A three by three thingy.
I guess on the outside I could have water.
Hmm.
I do wonder, though, if I can spout this.
But then we would need pipes, and how does that work?
You know, that's getting...
That's getting a little weird.
All of a sudden.
I think we just have to put water on the outside.
It's the only way.
That's an annoying path up here.
I need the handlebar.
So, one, two, three.
So that means...
It's going to be here.
Huh?
Oh, I got a flower, I think.
Let's get the handlebar.
It's perfect for this sort of situation.
That's right, I remembered where it was.
Yes, this is dog.
I can't not see this as a telephone!
Put it here.
Oh, I need to have an...
No, no, no, no, no, no.
Oh, my God.
There we go.
And then we switch hands.
So this is the process.
We grab.
We switch.
We...
Switch.
Deposit.
We're almost there.
Ow!
How does that hurt from there?
That's not even that big of a drop.
We have done it.
I need to make more harvesters.
I need three of them.
Add two more.
Oh, no, I need alloys.
You...
How am I lacking alloy?
Okay, we need to have an output alloy.
That feeds straight into my mouth.
We need to have a tube with alloys coming in non-stop that goes into my mouth.
I cannot be fed enough.
So, hold on.
We're making cobblestone and diorite and the side.
And the and the side is gonna blah, blah, blah here.
And alloy comes out.
Okay.
Let's just make an output right now.
Right here.
You see how it's waiting?
It can't wait to continue.
So I will...
I will just stand here like Homer in hell, you know, eating donuts.
Just into my mouth with the belt.
I have it open.
Feed me.
No, I need a chest.
That's what I really need.
Or something that can receive.
Let's take this one.
For now, at least.
And then instead of...
Oh, let me see here.
Can't...
Is it really that easy?
It is actually that easy.
And...
Is it really gonna make one at a time?
Wait, why is it not being filled?
Oh, wait, I'm an idiot!
Whoops.
It's over here.
And...
Here it comes.
It...
Hmm.
Yeah, it's not depositing.
I don't understand why that's not happening.
Okay, I'll just take him.
It's not ideal, but you know, it is what it is.
No!
I want to die.
There we go.
Green factory.
No, not now.
The pig is protecting me.
Don't want the boots.
Ow!
Oh, it's the saw.
What a horrible set of circumstances I find myself in.
No!
This is actually like hell.
This is my personal hell right now.
Why...
Why won't you grab it?
Okay.
Here we go.
I'm just gonna stand here.
This is the best I can do, guys.
I can't come up with a better solution.
I got 11.
Ah, come on.
Ah.
I got it.
I just need a little bit more.
Okay, that's it.
That was rough for my sanity.
And I think I needed four to make one, so we have at least enough for two.
Good.
Okay.
Harvester.
Sheets.
Sheets we got.
Then we needed, uh...
These.
One, two.
No more than two.
Because we don't have room up here anyway.
And then I need to devise a clever situation where I can absorb the stuff that's coming out of it.
Yeah, before we do, let's, um...
We'll plant some stuff.
Wait, I can probably even put bone meal inside of here.
That's maybe too next level.
Maybe that's too clever.
We should calm it down a little bit.
Oh, one more.
On...
One more over here.
Actually, this is kind of a big farm.
Look at this.
That's massive.
Need more dirt, though.
Wait, I have water over here I could have taken.
Oh!
Oh, thank God the water doesn't come down.
One, two, three, four.
Hey, it's perfect.
And we have water over here.
I just broke that!
You saw that!
Oh, never mind.
Grab the water.
No!
Oh, close it.
Bro.
There we go.
Actually, just look at the dirt one you take.
That's easier.
Where did that dirt come from?
One more?
Nice!
And look at that!
They're all being wet now.
Or wetted.
Is that the right word for that?
Wet it?
Then we need the chassis.
First, we gotta stop this thing, though.
Stop!
Now.
Oh, shit!
I have to, uh, do this first.
We don't need this.
Or this.
Ah, we do need that.
Yeah, we do need this.
Just gonna go that way.
Oops.
Oi!
What the fuck is happening here?
Okay, now we put them on.
There!
Oh my god, that looks incredible!
Love the way that looks.
I'm even gonna look- make this look even better.
Check.
I don't like this being here.
Looks- Oh, but it needs to be there.
But I will remove this then.
And then put one higher.
Not bad.
Although, obviously this needs to be bigger.
It's too small right now.
It's not pretty e- Either.
Dude, I'm breaking this somehow.
Constantly.
What the f- Yeah, you can't walk on them.
I guess that makes sense.
Just- Minimize the walking.
Now.
Oops.
No.
Switch.
Oh, I can't do it when it's underneath.
Maybe I'll have to start it first.
Here you go, baby!
And now?
Quickly, plant.
That will con- Oh my god, that's beautiful.
That is so incredibly beautiful.
What a design.
Okay.
Now the question is- It's gonna collect things.
We should have a chest.
And then we should have a deposit.
So I guess the portable storage thingy is the solution here.
The one we just pondered a little while ago.
Let's go make a couple of those.
Just one, actually.
Portable storage interface.
Shoot and casing.
I must have both of those.
Do I not have it?
You have a casing?
Kidding me?
It looks like that, okay.
No, I don't have it.
Let's make it.
Just iron.
Love when it's easy.
Oh, it makes four at a time.
Interesting.
Portable.
Dude.
I have one already.
Somewhere.
Unless I already- Yeah, there it is.
Found it.
So that's two.
And you have to connect them facing each other.
Yeah, look.
We're gonna put chests on top.
It's wonderful.
The thing is, though, how does it work then?
Is it gonna stop automatically?
And do we have to have like a...
Oh, I guess it's just when it's empty then it continues?
Huh, that may actually be the case.
Yeah, probably.
Let's see.
Oh, another thing we need to test real quick.
If I have a chute just sitting here like that.
I remove that and I throw an item down.
It all- Okay, good.
It automatically falls through.
That's fantastic.
Look.
Oh, that's beautiful!
That's exactly what a man needs.
Bam!
So let me see.
Let's say the deposit place is...
Maybe over here-ish.
Like, there.
Right here.
Where I'm standing right now.
This is it.
This is where it gets deposited.
We add a little extension that goes across.
Ah, but then it can't go through here.
Ah.
Yes, it can!
There's a gap!
That's the whole trick?
It's amazing.
Let's see what's down there.
Ah, the water's gonna come through then.
That's a problem.
It's actually not a problem.
It's not!
Because we have a chute!
Uh, first, let's, uh...
We're gonna quickly shoot it.
Go!
Hey, that was fast!
Okay.
Now.
Portable.
Storage.
Items move downward.
There we go.
Are you ready?
This is gonna face that way now.
But do they need a gap?
I think they had a gap.
There is a gap.
Okay.
So that doesn't work like that.
I guess we can make a little hole here.
This actually kinda looks cool, too.
I don't mind.
It may even be better.
What happened to my...
Oh.
Shoot!
Uh...
Now we're gonna have to put dirt back here.
There we go.
Super fast dirt.
And then this guy is gonna go...
Yeah, this is what I feared.
There we go!
We gotta stop this thing.
Stop!
And now...
On this one, we're gonna have a little extra on top.
Linear chassis.
Boom.
And...
Ah, the question is, though.
Will this be connected, then?
If I attach now.
Let's see.
It's not!
Okay.
Uh...
Maybe the...
Glue?
Oh my...
God!
What is happening?!
What
is happening?!
It's working!
They were kissing!
It's beautiful!
Now, Keith.
Ha ha ha ha ha ha, dude!
Okay, you ready?
We need chests now.
What happened here?
Oh, that's ugly now!
Me no like?
Uh...
Ah!
Look what I just found on the floor.
We're just gonna cover that up real quick.
Nobody's gonna see that.
There we go.
Beautiful.
Oh no, it's dripping water!
Oh, we can't have that.
We have a leak.
Crap.
We need to make beams here across, too.
We can't have these little...
No, no, no, no, no.
That's not gonna work.
Terrible.
Uh...
Yeah, chests is what we need.
Just a couple.
Just chests.
Or a barrel!
Hey, that may even look cooler.
Not sure if it'll work.
Oh.
It's here.
So I guess I just put it somewhere?
There's no way that works.
Let me put in some...
Let me do this.
We're gonna simulate.
It has grown a little bit.
And...
Here we go.
Oh!
Oh, my God.
I forgot.
There we go.
Okay.
Here we go.
And...
Will it collect the stuff that's, like, free-floating?
No!
Okay.
Uh, let me quickly...
Simulate the growing!
Drive-by exchange!
Oh, it takes a while, too!
That's sick!
Yo.
This is insane.
And it's gonna come down here, right?
Haha, look!
We can shoot it all the way down.
Uh...
Do I want to do that, though?
Hmm.
We can shoot it through the walls.
We need more shoots.
I love the shoots.
Eight more.
In fact, it's industrial-looking!
I don't mind having a shoot in the wall!
That's a nice shoot.
At the bottom, we're gonna do something else.
Also, can I somehow make this look nicer?
Oh, look at this!
That's pretty.
Very nice.
Dolle Garde!
Hahaha!
Uh, let me fill up my inventory.
Or empty it, I mean.
Empty that.
Uh, greenery.
There we go.
Let's put the...
No!
E-create!
It's the modern version of it.
Uh, maybe I keep this on me.
Okay, okay.
We gotta fix this leak!
I don't like this water dripping on my face.
Makes me uncomfortable.
Weird thing is, we don't even have enough wood for this.
Don't like that.
Then again, we don't need...
The same type of...
Maybe we make it industrial-looking.
Can I make something iron-ish?
Something a little more solid than a window, maybe?
And again, it is a window.
Maybe we wanna see the inner workings of the whole thing, you know?
Block of iron is maybe a little too aggressive.
I mean, we can make some iron windows.
Why not?
Or we put bars?
Nah, that's gonna drip through.
Oak windows!
Of course!
That is the answer!
We're oaking!
We have one there.
Oak.
That should do it.
Oh, hell yeah.
Tell me that doesn't look amazing.
You get to see the little...
Oh no, it's still dripping.
Why is it dripping here and not there?
I mean...
Here and not there.
That should not drip.
Oh, wait, it's...
Oh no.
We need more windows.
For some reason, the windows make it non-drippy.
Oh, that's even the wrong spot.
No, I broke it!
How did I accent up there anyway?
That makes no sense.
And it looks good too.
Kinda.
I'm not gonna say it's a masterpiece, because it ain't.
But, you know.
What do we think of this?
We gotta drip.
Drip.
We're not done dripping.
Dang.
In fact, it even looks better now.
Maybe I continue it all the way to here.
Wait, something fell in the water.
Also, I'm gonna have a little...
I need to find a way to get up there quick.
You know, we need some kind of axis hatch.
So that would be one...
One.
Okay, one.
Right...
Oh, we can't.
There's water.
I can't believe how well this is working.
This is so cool.
I love this part.
When they do that.
Please do it more.
You know what we could do?
Yo!
Oh, check it out.
We could have another portable storage interface here with a filter on it saying, Only taters, my lord.
Only here we're gonna have carrots.
And they all go their separate ways.
Dude.
Incredible.
Ha ha!
Damn.
I need to make this look pretty over here.
It's not pretty enough.
Maybe we can do something funky here.
See, that's cool.
It's like it's built into the whole thing.
In fact, we can make it better.
Watch this.
What?
That's not what I did.
Ah!
Nah, I'm not feeling it.
It was better the other way.
In fact, maybe...
Nope.
That's not good either.
Let's just stick to this.
That's nice.
And then we're gonna do this.
Cover it in chocolate.
Ha ha ha!
You know, you like it.
Dude, that is...
Honestly, that's fire.
Bop!
Ha ha ha!
That's so good!
Can I wanna cover this water?
What do we cover it with?
More flapjacks, maybe.
Maybe see-through or, um...
Windows or something.
Something's gotta happen here.
I love this so much.
And look...
Ah, right!
This doesn't work anymore now.
Why is that?
Is it too slow, maybe?
It's because this one is dominating the rotation, not that one.
So...
Oh!
I think this one simply needs to be over here.
Nope.
Wait, hold on.
Why is that not working now?
So before, we had rotation coming in here.
And...
Oh, it's rotating this way now, which means it's pulling up.
But it can't go up anymore because of this.
So when I did this, that's when I reversed it.
But this reversion is actually being overwritten by this one.
That's what's happening.
So if I remove this shaft...
And this one.
And put it, uh...
I don't know, here?
No, wait.
Give me the lever.
Isn't it...
It is rotating, look!
It's even rotating the right way, so I need to...
Ah, this one needs to be in between.
Yeah.
But there's no room for that, because it's...
Hmm, that's a...
That's a weird one.
I guess I can put it on the other side.
Yeah, that's actually a good idea.
Put it over here instead.
Like that.
And then we rod it.
Like so.
Watch.
Down we go!
But very slow, though.
Maybe a little too slow.
So we gotta speed that up.
But it looks cool, doesn't it?
Like the ultimate...
Oh, wait.
Let's not actually get down.
Oops.
Oh, I can't climb all this in motion!
I fucked up.
Oh, I can't get back up.
That's fine.
Not that bad.
Yeah, that is painfully slow, let's be honest here.
That's not good.
I have an idea, though.
It's not all over.
We will embrace the cog.
Make your jokes.
We shall embrace it.
We will embrace the industrial look.
And we will do the gear reduction...
Right here!
Eh!
What?
Oh, shit.
Oh, no.
Huh?
Wait, why does that suck it up like that?
Uh-oh.
Quick!
Okay, well...
Better than nothing, I guess.
This...
Okay.
I have no idea what just happened.
Why did that happen just now?
I mean, I guess I removed these.
Maybe that's the problem.
But I was gonna embrace the cog, so I...
I...
Why does it do that?
It's like pulling it up slightly first, and then going down.
That's weird.
Now, stop.
Oh, shit.
Oh.
We gotta put this in first, and then...
Stop!
Nice!
Okay, there it is.
Okay, good.
So, this is rotating this way now.
We're gonna use a big cog.
That looks cool, too!
Now a small one.
Spinning faster.
Big one.
Yo!
I like it!
I think.
Let's have this...
There.
And then...
I don't have a big cog.
Only have a small...
There's no good spot for this now.
I can't...
I can't go too low with it, you know?
Then it's gonna be bad.
Let me see.
Yeah, it breaks.
Damn!
Maybe...
No, that's not gonna work.
The only place is here.
And I don't like that.
What it is?
Huh?
Oh, right.
Doesn't work either.
Shit.
We have to use a rod.
I didn't want it to come to the...
Oh!
But I was about to say...
Oh, no.
Don't go anywhere.
I was about to say...
Don't we have a way to have gear reduction without making...
You know, big gears?
I think we discovered that last time.
This is like the whole thing.
I just forget what it was.
Let's see.
I'll know it when I see it.
I mean, I'll know it when I...
See the name of it.
Maybe that one, actually.
Well, let's just keep looking.
I think it's this one.
Gearshift.
What's that?
Oh!
This may be it!
I think this is the one.
Nuggets encasing.
Really don't need this glass right now.
A painting?
That's...
Going back over here.
Spiders.
Okay.
Why not?
I'm on my last stake, by the way.
That's unfortunate.
But now we have wheat!
Forever!
Look!
At some point, wheat should fall down.
It's just not growing yet.
You'll see.
This will be filled with wheat and thyme.
Oh!
Hold on.
I want to automatically bake the bread, too.
That's totally possible.
I think.
I mean, yeah.
Okay.
But can I not just use this, maybe?
Seems a little overkill just for that, doesn't it?
We'll see what we can do.
But I want to...
I want to do that.
Yeah.
I was making the thingy.
So I need...
Small debitura.
Chain.
Before I craft it, I really should have checked this.
Oh, no.
This is not actually what...
What...
Yeah.
Oh, no.
No!
Wait, wait, wait!
This may...
Yeah.
This is it.
Source?
Yeah.
When powered, the speed transmitted to other chain drives in the row is double.
Okay, we need power for that.
Okay!
And this?
Oh, we don't know what that is!
Maybe it's just powered, actually.
Maybe that's what it...
But why does it look like?
Why does it have a little red window on it?
Hold on.
Experimentation.
Let's give it power.
Watch it come down.
It's gonna come down.
There's gonna be a little...
Oh!
Hoey!
Hehehehe!
It works!
This is a big deal, guys!
I have never, ever had an automatic way of getting items from a farm like this.
This is wild to see.
Unbelievable.
Cannot believe that works.
Okay, so now...
Why, uh...
You know what?
I may actually have the item I need.
Let me just check here.
It looks like that one!
Doesn't it?
Electron tube?
I think we got it.
I don't like e-create.
Sheets.
Tube?
Let's just make six of them.
Chain.
Okay.
I'm gonna ponder that.
Oh, it's the same one.
Okay.
You got it.
So, let's get rid of this.
Don't need that anymore.
Don't fall in the lava!
That's actually getting a little risky.
Let me take care of that.
Just so we don't have an accident.
Now, my question is...
If I go...
If I put that there...
Put power to it...
There's not gonna be enough space.
So, maybe we go around in a circle?
My goodness.
I think we're gonna go around in a circle.
Watch me circle this.
Ah, there may not be enough room for that.
But we'll see.
Oh, and it doesn't go that way.
But I can make it go that way.
Nice!
Now we need power.
Right, doesn't work like that.
There we go.
It's powered!
Notice the rotation?
Now watch.
Is that faster?
I can't tell.
That's not faster.
Wait a minute.
No, not this one.
Ah, actually it works.
We can just go to the next.
It's powered.
In it goes.
That's the same speed.
I don't understand this.
Let's do a fuel test.
Shit doesn't make sense.
So therefore we test.
Let's do exactly what they did in that video.
Power.
Let me crank it.
Look how fast they are!
Wait, why is it working now?
On the side.
Crank it.
Oh!
I was going this way.
I need to go that way.
I see it now.
I understand.
That makes a lot of sense.
There's a chain inside.
So what would be the best way to do this?
Let me think.
We obviously have to connect it.
Oops.
Wrong one.
But I think we have to connect the other way then.
This thing is going to come down in a sec.
Wait.
It needs to go that way.
That way now.
So maybe we go across now?
Instead of going around?
Yeah.
That's probably better.
Let me just do a temporary blockage.
Like this.
Now we want to put this next to it.
And this should be faster now.
It ain't.
Oh, it's because it's not powered.
Power.
It's faster.
It's going to be even faster.
We're not done fastering.
I can't see the fastness.
Is it faster?
Wait a minute.
Something's wrong.
Show it to me again.
What happened?
So you...
When power to speed transmitted to other chain drivers and the row is doubled.
Okay.
Oh.
So it's just the same for all of them here.
All right.
So I got to have multiple to go faster.
Yeah.
They're both 32 now.
Shit.
Got it.
So I could probably just put another.
Let me see here.
Chain.
This should be that easy, I guess.
And now we just got to power that.
Let's see.
Nah.
Okay.
We may have to have a little one in between.
Wait.
How the fuck?
This don't work.
You can't do that, it seems.
Interesting.
So I think what I need to do is to have one in between her.
Like that.
And then we go like here.
Now we power this.
Let me...
I don't want to get rid of that.
I'm too scared.
It's going to fall down.
Can I...
Hold on.
Let me undo this...
For now.
How does that work again?
I just...
Right?
Now it should be totally cool.
Nice!
Okay.
No more worrying about that.
Now let's see.
Let's try and put power to this now.
It's not going to work because it's...
This is not going to work.
I can tell already.
But...
Just for completeness sake, I'm going to...
Attempt it.
Goddammit.
I need...
I need more power.
Now we do another chain.
Yeah.
It doesn't work.
Crap!
Okay.
Well.
But what you can do probably is...
Go this way.
No, wait.
How would you do that?
Now, yeah.
You can probably do that.
Yeah, actually.
So watch.
Now we go across.
Actually, I put this in here.
My inventory is terrible, dude.
I can't think straight.
So what if I do this here now?
Right?
Power.
And now we put one next to it.
Wait.
I stopped the road.
Oh!
Oops.
I removed the gearbox.
Yeah!
That works, baby!
That's how you do it!
Okay!
Neat!
So now we can bring this across.
Oh, yeah.
Oh, this is so compact and cool.
Maybe we rod it like that.
Oh!
And then we bring this there.
No, that's the wrong one.
Uh.
I need more.
Chain.
Tubes.
And chain drives.
They look almost the same, don't they?
Ah, but if I go across there, that's gonna mess it up, isn't it?
I think it is.
We may have to go like that, and then that way.
Oh, and that's gonna be...
That's actually so pretty.
So pretty.
And the side alloys.
Yeah, I got it!
Very nice.
So, here.
And then...
This one!
And then we somehow apply power!
And then...
Normal chain drive!
Chain drive!
Right here!
It's gonna be even faster now!
Now, to bring it across...
The last stretch here...
Is going to be a little funky, I think.
Uh...
How do we bring this to there?
Because now it's going this way, right?
Uh...
I can't connect these two.
I can go this way, I guess?
But then I'm gonna ruin my water ceiling.
That's not pretty.
Hmm.
Maybe there's a way to use a gearbox without...
Like, only in one corner, so to speak.
Do I even have one?
Do I have this?
Yeah, it's gonna break.
I will say, though, I kind of like this look.
It looks...
Kind of nice, doesn't it?
Oh, wait!
It's just like that, I guess.
But now...
Oh, it's super easy!
I have it, I have it.
Now we just need a gear shift.
Or, sorry, a gearbox.
We almost had it.
I also need the gear shift at some point.
The gear shift is the one that reverses the rotation.
Yeah, that's gonna break there.
I think I do need to use the encased chain drive there.
Now it's there.
Uh...
Maybe on...
Maybe we bring it...
Hmm.
I mean, I guess I...
I could...
Oh, this is...
This is another...
Oops.
I don't think there's a way to do what I'm trying to do here.
I'm trying to be really clever with it, right?
It's not doing me any favors.
Oh, wait!
Unless I rotate this bad boy!
Like that?
And now we're almost there.
Let me see.
I need...
I just need to connect these without touching that.
Yikes.
I don't think that's possible.
Maybe with a vertical gearbox, actually.
That breaks.
That goes down.
That's close!
Look!
Why can't I bring that over there immediately?
It breaks.
What if I put it like...
There's gotta be a way to put it without...
Hmm.
You know what I mean?
Like, I need the flat side to be there, but I can't place it without it breaking first.
That's the problem.
Okay.
Whatever.
I guess we'll just have to make a path through the water here.
I don't like it, but...
You know.
It is what it is.
Okay.
That's...
Oh, no.
It's dripping now!
Can we stop it?
Nice!
Okay!
The drip can be stopped with a little...
Drip protector.
So now this is rotating.
So I guess it's...
All we gotta do is now just bring it this way and that in.
And that way.
You know?
Then we're home free.
Oof!
Man, oh man.
Like that.
Now we rot it.
And...
Also, what is this?
Directional gearshift.
I'm not sure.
I need gearbox.
Cockwheels.
Gearshift?
No, gear...
I keep saying gearshift.
Ah!
Fuck!
I forgot.
Hmm.
I have an idea.
I can fix it.
Watch this.
And then?
Yeah!
Oh!
Wait.
No, not the crank!
I need the...
Button.
The lever thingy.
Where are you at?
Did I put you in here?
I did, indeed.
Now, question.
If I put this here, will it block the leakage?
Not that one.
Come on!
Dude, hell yeah.
That's crazy.
It actually works.
Hey!
We have done it!
Now we just gotta connect the rest?
Oh my good.
That is incredible looking.
I am so proud of myself.
What a wonderful display.
And look at this.
We're gonna make it prettier too.
We're gonna do stuff like this and that.
I mean...
Tell me this isn't wonderful.
It may be a little slow still.
Maybe we could have made it a little faster.
In fact...
Yeah!
We can have another thingy here.
Oh wait.
I haven't even powered this yet.
That's why it's slow.
Right.
Let's power it.
Oh no!
Man!
The only fucking hole I had!
That's crazy.
Where the hell is the thing?
This makes no sense.
I feel like I didn't deserve to die there.
That was not on me.
I didn't do it.
I'm going down to collect it.
I can't believe that happened!
What a sad day.
Oh ho ho ho ho ho ho ho ho!
Actual god.
Oh man.
But I lost all my experience.
Dude, I'm level 7.
I had 29 before.
This is going to take me 50 years to get back.
That's crazy.
Oh yeah.
I put a drill there.
Through.
Now how do I get back up?
Where's my...
There it is.
Okay.
Let's just dig I guess.
I cannot believe that happened.
Hey look.
I made a little staircase here.
Looks like I've done this before, huh?
Oh man.
What a bummer.
To die like that.
I have no idea where these items went.
Did they break or something?
Like...
Where did that rope go?
And the floor is...
It's like the game was...
Conspiring against me there.
Very weird.
I don't even have the rope anymore.
It just up and disappeared.
Wait.
Oh wait.
Uh...
Ah.
It's going to grab it now.
Oh it went up and broke I guess.
Okay.
Yeah look.
Now it takes it.
Yeah it doesn't stop does it?
Yeah.
And then I fell down.
Yeah okay.
I see how it works.
That's so funny.
It made a little hole.
Held it there and then I fell through the hole.
That is kind of funny.
I will admit it.
Ah well.
It is what it is.
Let's not cry over spilled milk.
I will now perform a...
C section.
And then we need one over here too.
But how do I do that?
What's the good spot for this?
Wait how do...
How do I power that one?
Wait...
No.
I feel like this question should be easy to answer.
And I don't have an easy answer.
Is it the block of redstone?
Somehow.
If I...
Yo.
Actually.
There it is.
Ah.
But it's...
Yeah.
Okay.
Never mind.
Why did I search for wind?
I needed...
Oh yeah.
Window.
Right.
That's why I searched for wind.
I guess I can remove this.
No.
I cannot even do that.
Man.
This is a real mystery.
I can't...
I wish I could put redstone dust in the ceiling.
Right?
This one's rotating.
That's rotating.
If I...
Put one there.
Then I can't...
I have an idea.
What we can do...
Is...
The following.
And I need to count.
Okay.
It's the last one.
Next one.
Second to last.
There we go.
It kissed me.
Okay.
Now it should not disturb the bottom part.
We should be able to put a torch.
Ah.
But that is just the ugliest, isn't it?
I don't like that at all.
Then we can cover it up again.
Actually, I know how to do this.
Wait a sec.
This is in the wrong spot.
Yeah?
Huh?
Oh, it's gonna flap the jack, dude!
Or use one of these.
It don't work like that!
I give up.
I need something made out of something else.
What is it?
Oh, ingots.
Oh, I thought I just took those.
This should work.
Okay.
Here we go.
Ready?
Did my torch fall down?
No.
Wait.
How did that end up in the basket again?
I don't know.
I'm losing my mind.
Also, did I remove the water by doing that?
Is it now like a reduced water situation?
Maybe the humble slab?
Let's see if there's a W for the slab or if it's not a common L.
Get up there.
You can have water?
Wait.
You can have water in half a block?
Oh, hell no.
Absolutely not.
Wish I had a hammer right now so I could drop on your face.
But I do have a bow.
Sayonara, bitch.
In fact...
Let's have some lights up here.
Oh, I can't.
You know why?
Common slab L.
This is a rare slab W.
I'll say that.
There's a small W here.
I will admit it.
I cannot believe that there's water on top of a slab.
That blows my mind.
God, I need to fix my inventory.
I am losing my mind.
In.
This goes in here.
In there.
Put it in there.
Redstone.
It's over there.
Oh, my God.
Now slab.
Also, where did that creeper come from?
Oh, maybe it is a little dark up here.
Wait a sec.
Can I put a torch on this?
And have it spin with the...
No way, right?
I don't want to deactivate it, because it's going to break a lot of stuff when I do.
Sorry.
But now, if I do this...
There is no fucking way.
That's news to me, guys.
This blows my damn mind.
And I wonder if this is a way...
Oh, oh.
No, thanks.
I wonder if that is a way for me to...
Stop spillage?
Like...
Nope.
I just saw a...
I just saw a drop fall.
Oh, no.
It's still spilling.
What are my...
Red...
Oh.
My hand.
Okay.
There it is.
Well, you know what?
I didn't have any XP anyway.
Wait, why is music playing?
What the hell just happened?
What the fuck?
I think I crashed my game.
My game crashed.
I saw how crashed the game.
Wow.
What is happening, bro?
That doesn't even make sense.
Come on.
Load inside the game, please.
Wow.
That's my words exactly.
Dude, I...
Wait, what?
I got saved!
Yes, sir!
You know what?
Bop!
That's right!
No more of that!
That's beautiful!
Beu...
Wait.
How do I have a torch right now when I already placed it here?
There's something going on.
Something's going on here, guys!
We still got the drippage, though.
That's the problem.
Is that...
It's the creeper.
He's still out there.
Whoops!
Didn't mean to do that.
Whoopsie-dosey.
Let's not fall in that hole again.
Okay?
Dude, I got so mad just now falling through that hole again.
Okay, uh...
Let's glue it all together, shall we?
Here comes the glue.
I...
Dude, I can't wait to see this part in the VOD because I need to see how this transpired.
I need to see what the hell happened here.
So I fell down.
I died.
I stood up from the computer, walked out.
I accidentally hit a music button, I guess, on my way out.
And the game crashed.
And then somehow I didn't die.
I got reverted back in time.
That is a crazy set of...
I don't know.
Happenstances, you know?
Kind of wild.
Now, uh...
Here.
There.
I'm now an expert at gluing, of course.
Uh...
Hold on.
Whoa!
We got a door open!
He was trying to enter my abode.
My private domicile.
Let me go to sleep.
I see.
Wasn't lying when it said there were monsters nearby.
What are you trying to do here, huh?
Get out of my house!
Thank you.
How are you getting here, anyway?
Is there not enough light?
Where are we liking light?
Oh, that's so neat, too.
We can put that on the...
thingies?
Let's do that.
That's pretty.
All right!
Uh...
I was gluing.
I'm an expert gluer, is what I was about to say.
So we're gonna check...
Oh!
Here?
Wait.
Wait, how the...
Here?
There?
Oh, yeah.
There!
And...
And now...
I need a little bit of some wood.
Oh!
Didn't mean to do that.
Boom!
That should be it.
So now...
Now...
There we go!
Hmm.
Why is it not...
Maybe now?
Oops.
Wait, it's spinning that...
Wait, wait.
Hold on.
Spinning...
Spinning left now.
Spinning right...
Wait, what the...
What the hell?
Why doesn't this work?
Oh!
I know why!
D'ah!
Ha ha ha ha ha ha!
I forgot about the hole I made!
I mean...
The blockage!
I was blocking it!
There we go!
And now...
Here to there...
Oops.
There.
No, no, no, no, no.
Wait, how...
There we go.
There we go!
You ready?
Boom!
I'm losing my mind!
Oh!
It's that one!
I think.
Now we go back up.
Not there.
Yes, actually.
There we go!
What the hell?
I'm losing my mind!
Back down.
Oh!
I see.
Hold on.
I understand.
I forgot we had stuff down here.
Dude, let me just remove this.
Good enough?
Yeah.
Now remove this.
Oh, I thought I was gonna die again!
I...
I think I would have cried.
If it happened.
Okay.
Here we go.
Yeah!
We got the speed back!
Wonderful!
That is actually so cool.
But we're not done.
We're not done.
Because?
No, we're done.
We're not done!
We have drippage.
Let me see where it's dripping.
Dripping here?
It's probably dripping there too.
Sweet!
It works there.
Okay.
So that means...
It's time for the flappies.
Yes!
No.
This one...
This last one goes away.
Drippage!
Fixed!
Look!
It's pretty.
And it fits with the rest of the aesthetic.
Okay, that one doesn't want to cooperate for some reason.
Hmm, okay.
Oh, wait.
These need to be connected.
Except, uh...
Rotation is not going that way anymore, is it?
No, it's not.
Ah, that's annoying.
I guess we can gearbox that.
That's probably a gearbox situation.
Also, let me just pull this up again.
Very nice.
This mod is amazing.
I love that I can do something like this.
Oops.
No more steaks!
We have officially run out.
Uh, I guess...
Potatoes are bag on the menu.
It looks a little messy up here, but I think there's beauty in it.
This is straight up...
Beautiful.
What can I say?
And all of this power is coming from the windmill up top that's producing wheat!
For me at the same time.
I think just...
That in itself is so damn cool.
You know?
I need more, um...
Uh...
Fences.
I don't like this hack with the fence, though.
I feel like we should change that.
Somehow.
That can be done better.
But let's save that for another day.
For now, I'm just gonna make it a little more pretty here.
One there, and then let's put one...
Hey!
That doesn't connect at all.
Damn.
Nah, there's no good spot for it now.
Actually, there is.
There is a good spot.
There, see?
And then we connect.
Even though, this is not nice.
I don't like that.
But you know, it is what it is.
Maybe we even have a little...
That's fine.
This is good.
This is cool.
The only problem is, of course, how to get back up.
But I guess when you're down there, you can use the rope.
Right?
So let's say we go down.
Now I wanna go explore in my cave.
I like that I can still walk around like this.
That's nice.
So I can't climb to roam now, because it's moving.
But as soon as it's stopped, I should be able to...
Whoa.
Bro has never seen an elevator in his life.
And now...
I can climb up!
It's a bit of a hack, I guess, right now.
But, you know, it works.
Even found some sink.
Like,
good enough for me.
And then from here, guys, we're gonna have a little ride.
We're gonna make a little rollercoaster from here to explore the mines.
It's gonna be great.
Oh!
Guys, I just had an incredible idea.
Regarding the trains.
Dude.
We're gonna have trains coming up top, right?
They're gonna drive into a station.
They're gonna be lowered.
Into down here.
And then it goes...
Down in the caves.
It's coming around.
Into here.
And it goes...
Up again.
They have that in real life, by the way.
Or at least...
I think the Germans have something where they put a train on one of those things.
And they rotate with the tracks.
You know what I mean?
We're gonna...
We're gonna do it.
That sounds so cool.
Now I'm gonna...
Climb up here.
Yeah...
And then...
Oh no!
We almost were perfect.
We need a slab.
I hate to say it, but...
We do.
A singular slab, maybe.
Boop!
It's not pretty.
In fact, it's ugly.
But, uh...
You know.
In fact, I think I'm gonna slap some more.
Just to...
Switch it up a bit.
No, those need to be wired up later.
Somehow.
That's ugly.
I hate it.
That's pretty.
Well, that was a bit of a detour with the elevator.
But we got it fixed.
Eh, it looks better.
Maybe.
Okay, I was doing trains, wasn't I?
That was the whole point.
Yeah, this is broken now, but it's okay.
The problem with trains...
Is that I still don't have the components I need.
I believe.
Which is a...
Crying shame.
So, yeah.
This house is starting to take shape.
I especially love the fact that from outside it looks like a normal house.
But then when you go inside...
You know, all kinds of complicated stuff is happening.
Machinery left and right.
It's like a whole smorgasbord of inventions.
Like this right here is beautiful.
And, you know what else?
We can probably make this even faster by just putting more sails.
Let's do that!
More sails!
Let's see how far we can take this.
And maybe we can even get the achievement now that we're at it.
Somewhere there's an achievement for this.
All the way over here.
Look.
Simple windmill of maximum strength.
Oh, no.
We need alloys.
I guess we're gonna go eat some.
Eating time.
Conveyor belt into my mouth.
Let's assume the position.
I wish it would stack more at a time so it doesn't have to do this.
In fact, I guess it will stack a bit so I can clean my glasses while it's doing it.
It's gonna stack three, it seems.
Wait.
Unless I picked up multiple.
No.
And then it keeps going.
Yeah, so it prepares three.
No, it prepares two on the belt and one inside there.
I think a lot are gonna come out too.
Ah, two at a time.
Okay.
I don't know what maximum strength is.
Like, I guess I'll just make a bunch.
Ow.
That should probably do it.
Sticks I have.
I guess I still have a bunch of wool.
Should be fine.
37.
That's quite a bit.
46 sails.
Surely, we're gonna assemble a maximum strength windmill with this.
Oh, I have to stop this now.
Oh my god.
There we go.
Okay.
I need some light up here.
I probably need to go a little higher.
Dude.
There.
I just need to have...
One on each, like that.
Oh, I just walk.
One, two.
Up.
Maybe I extend it a little bit out as well now.
I have 28.
Yeah, okay.
That's probably fine.
Get reach.
God damn it.
Huh?
Oh, I need to stand.
I don't think I have enough.
It's gonna be uneven.
May have enough.
Just barely.
Oh, wait.
I, uh...
Alright, that's fine.
A little uneven.
It works.
And the rest should just...
Work?
Oh, that's ugly as hell.
Ew.
Yikes.
Let's see.
Damn, that's fast!
What the fuck, dude?
Look at it go!
Holy shit!
Adding sails is totally worth...
Okay, but we're not done.
We need more sails.
I need this achievement now.
I gotta get it.
More!
Did I use all my...
I didn't.
Nice.
But I used all my wool, I think.
Oh, no.
No, wait.
I have it in my hand.
Nice.
Uh, I think it sticks, then.
Sail.
Twelve.
Oh, please be enough.
Please.
I'm sorry.
I'm gonna stop you right...
Oh, I'm scared.
Can I take damage from that?
No.
Okay.
But I can get pushed around.
Wish me luck.
I'm actually gonna remove this bottom part, because I think it looks better.
Then we're gonna extend upwards.
One, two, three.
Dup, dup, dup.
Dup, dup.
Dup.
Oh, come on!
Are we not there yet?
Maybe it needs to be started first.
Brother!
How big can you make this?
Now I'm...
I have no more...
Okay.
I'm gonna continue.
We're making this bigger and bigger and bigger.
This one needs to go hard.
Time to...
Hulp.
Some more.
What?
Oh.
Oh my god.
Surely this is enough now.
Maybe we go to 15.
Just to be absolutely safe.
And...
Boom.
Look at the way it's rotating.
The way it just stops suddenly, though, looks a little weird, doesn't it?
I don't know if I like that.
But, you know, it is what it is.
Uh...
Sales.
16 more sales!
Come on, this is it.
Will this be enough, guys?
I say yes!
This is the one.
It's happening now.
Here we go.
Up, up, up, up, up, up, up, up, up, up.
We got six left.
That's two.
Oh, shit.
Oh my god, please.
Have it up!
Oh, yeah!
Oh.
Damn.
No!
Are you ready?
Here it comes.
And...
No way!
Also, dude, how fast is this elevator now?
Because...
Right now, this is...
This is gonna go hard, isn't it?
Damn!
Shit's fast, yo!
Wow!
Who would've thunk?
Well, there you go.
All right.
Where are my taters at?
What the...
Oh, they're in my hand.
Stop doing that!
I nearly had an aneurysm from the door.
We need more wool, guys.
I suddenly have a need for wool.
Good thing I have shears.
Because I'm not done.
That's right.
We're gonna bring them some food.
Look!
I'm using two slots.
Shit.
See that?
That's what you guys would've done, right?
This is the kind of sick, demented stuff you guys are doing.
Okay.
That wasn't a lot of wool, but I think it's enough.
Trust.
It sticks again.
Twelve more.
Come on, this is it.
Guys, is this it?
I say...
No.
I say no.
I hate to say it, but I say it...
I think it's a no.
Stop!
Oh, man.
Not to get up there.
Okay.
Same procedure as last time.
I'm stuck.
Oh, my God.
This...
Oh!
Sorry.
I'm okay.
There's a war inside of me.
Six.
One.
Two.
Three.
Four.
Five.
Six.
Hup!
Oh, I got...
God damn it, dude.
No, I can't get up.
Oh, man.
What even is happening?
Ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha.
Ah, shit.
All right, here we go.
This is it, surely.
What do you mean?
Ah,
I'm gonna...
I'm gonna give up.
Fuck, dude.
This achievement is crazy, dude.
Insane achievement.
Hardest achievement in the game.
Damn.
Holy crap.
It probably needs to be twice as big as it is now, even.
I can see it, you know.
Well, actually, hold on.
We could also Hail Mary this.
I got one Endicite Alloy.
Ah, but I don't even have a...
Guys?
If there's a sheep that is grown right now, we're doing it with the last.
Thank you.
We even get the...
How many did we...
Did I not pick it up?
Stop escaping!
We got three.
Nice.
That's even better.
I thought I only got one.
Oh, we're gonna wait for them to grow up, I guess.
Let's...
Seal.
No!
I...
I need...
Okay, you know what?
I can just attach it to the bottom.
We're testing anyway, right?
Okay, now.
Fuck it.
We're just gonna do this.
Come on!
Ah, go fuck yourself.
That's it.
I'm done.
No more.
Uh...
Damn.
This is an insane one.
Let me cook some sink in anger.
There you go.
No.
There.
Here.
In.
Uh, this is scaring me.
Holding.
So let me just do that.
Shears.
There.
Clean inventory.
We did it.
Well, almost.
And look how fast this is going now.
Damn!
That is insane.
Oh yeah?
You guys wanna have fun?
Noobs like to party?
Hello.
Oh, you died from one shot?
How on earth?
Oh, you got lucky there.
Look at him.
He's medicine.
Yeah, you don't like the medicine, do you?
Vmed.
Wonderful.
Hooligans have been taken care of.
Now.
Trains.
Can we figure it out, dammit?
Let's just, you know, just for...
Peace of mind.
I'm gonna put down some tracks before I lose it.
Because I'm actually close to losing it.
Oh.
Yeah, look at that.
Oh, cool.
No, just go straight for now.
Dang, that looks cool.
Cool.
Wow.
Now we need some wheels.
Let's see what we have in terms of wheels.
We may have to make some rubber ones.
Maybe that's what we need to get the inspiration to make the metal ones.
You know?
Rubber, rubber, rubber.
Wheel.
Maybe a small tire?
We need shafts.
Tire?
There's no way I can put that on the thing, right?
Hmm.
Must be placed on the front of a wheel mount.
Oh.
Wheel mount, huh?
Wheel mount.
Oh!
I see...
Oh, okay.
I probably need this for the train as well, then.
Spring and sheet.
I don't think I have a spring.
Nuggets and plates.
Now, wheel mount.
Needed a casing.
Which I have.
Mount.
Let me see.
Oh!
Okay.
Dude.
That's a big wheel.
I expected that to be way smaller.
I do wonder, though...
Can I somehow remove this...
rubber?
Make it go on the...
rails?
I have expected something to pop up as a new...
thing doing this.
Maybe nothing about wheels.
What else is train like?
Oh!
Maybe it's something to do...
Hold on.
I have an idea.
It's probably something to do with this stuff over here.
In the...
Let me see.
Recipe sequence.
It's probably this one.
Engine assembly.
Or even this one.
Gyroscopic mechanism.
Deploy.
Cockwheel shaft.
Brass nuggets.
Brass specifically, by the way.
This one's easy.
Saw.
And press.
Just an iron sheet.
But eight times!
Really?
Uh, I can do that.
Let's make another saw.
Let's make another press as well, since we're at it.
And we need some belts.
Shafts we got.
I think we got it all.
Oh, and the input for that was...
Um...
What was it?
Gyro something?
Oh no, wait.
It was the other one.
Iron sheets.
And I have those.
I have four of them.
But we need...
I wonder if I need eight of those, or if I need to do the same one eight times, you know?
Uh, I guess I'll find out.
Sink ingots.
Let's turn those into those.
Let's go to the factory!
Man, I want to fill this up so bad with wheels.
I can't tell you how much I want that right now.
It's gonna be so poggers when I figure it out.
Okay, now.
Let me hijack some of this rotational energy.
Let's make one right next to this!
Same procedure.
I could also just replace one of these right now.
Keep it simple.
I am lacking a chest, though.
Now, let's just keep this in case I want to make more rails later.
I'm gonna hate myself.
Best part is we can use this rotation here.
Hey, that's so dope!
Look at that!
I need another chest.
Ah, but wait a sec!
We need to go in a circle here.
This is my theory, at least.
So, we need to go, like...
Here now?
Here?
No, let's go...
There?
And then...
Here?
There?
I need more shafts.
Which means I need more...
I need to...
Hulp a little bit.
Hulp.
Gimme, gimme.
There we go.
Shaft!
Sleep.
Hmm, wait, wait, wait, wait.
Uh...
Yeah, that works, I guess.
And then we extend this.
That's gonna be a little annoying.
Hey, I guess I can...
Ah, but hold on.
They need to be reversed now.
Whoops.
Oh yeah, I see the problem.
We need reversers.
Dang!
You know what, actually?
Let's do it manually.
I need to see if I'm even understanding what this eight times means.
I need to see if it works like that.
The way I think it works, at least.
Where did my other chest go?
Now I need these weird funnels.
Forgot how to make them.
Oh, hell yeah, I can make them.
Oh!
Just the amount I needed, too.
It's wonderful.
Now.
It was saw, and then press, right?
So let's do saw.
Right here.
And press.
Oh, let me...
Wait, why can't I do this?
Is it because it's active?
What?
I can't click on it now.
Oh, I'm using...
I see.
Huh.
Right.
Okay, now.
And now this one needs to spin as well.
But, is it gonna spin the right way?
That's the question.
It's not, is it?
Shit.
I need a, uh...
Whatever this is.
Is it sequenced gearshift or whatever?
No.
Gear.
I think it's that one.
It's just the gearshift.
Redstone, dust, cockwheel, and andesite casing.
Don't have a...
Cockwheel.
Maybe I have it home.
I hope I do.
Look how fast it's spinning.
Nice.
And redstone I have as well.
Maybe I just make two of them, you know?
Just a half.
Good to have.
Dude, I love that it's two blocks across.
It's going to look so nice.
I wonder how smooth it's gonna feel to ride.
Because there's no jacket up and downs, right?
Yep, that'd be spinning the wrong way.
So now we apply a little bit of...
Redstone.
I need some cobblestone.
Uno cobblestone.
It's all a man needs.
I forgot what I was making.
I have no idea what I'm making.
Oh yeah, right.
Leaver.
Here we go.
And there it is.
Now we just need the presser, I think.
What are we making here anyway?
I forget what I was experimenting with.
Oh yeah, the engine assembly.
Right.
So, process and press.
Press, press, press.
Bop.
Like that.
I'm gonna use the rotation up here.
Bop.
Like that.
Very cool.
I'm even gonna make it look nice.
Like this.
And that should be it?
Let's try it.
One.
Oh, wait.
Funnel.
Incomplete engine assembly.
Ah.
I mean, obviously this is not ideal.
But, you know.
Hey, this is how people were doing at the beginning of the Industrial Revolution.
People were standing on these.
Don't forget.
They were at the assembly line doing this shit, you know.
This is the real experience.
Wait, what?
Hold on.
I don't understand.
Engine.
I should stop trying to fucking write on the keyboard without looking at the keyboard.
I will never be able to do it.
Oh, there's only a 50...
I thought it was 80%.
Wow!
Okay, okay, dude.
We gotta...
We gotta automate this.
I can't.
I can't do this again.
We have to go around.
Wait a sec.
Wait!
Are we not just gonna sequence a bunch of Tom Hollands?
Think about it.
Oh, I may not have enough iron for this.
Dang.
That's gonna cost a lot.
Wait!
I'm cooking some.
It's okay.
No.
Get him away from me.
So we basically Tom Holland from the chest all around back to the front chest.
Oh, wait a sec.
They need gravity.
There's like a bunch of ways to transport items.
There's gotta be a quick way to do this.
Let me see.
What's a quick way to do this?
Maybe the auger shaft, but I honestly, I don't know how it works exactly.
Optical sensor.
Spring.
Maybe it's like, maybe a shoot system horizontal.
I don't know if it can go horizontal though.
I mean, we don't need to do this right now.
I'm just being extremely lazy.
That's me being wildly lazy.
What about the, uh, the throwing thing?
Wait, I have it.
We just, we just ended on that and flip it back to the first.
Dude, I forgot what it was called.
Do I have it outside?
Oh my god, dude.
I hate not remembering what the name of it was.
Weighted ejector!
That's it!
And I think it needed to be cranked.
Oh shit, it needed to be cranked.
But that's okay.
We have, we have cranking power.
It's fine.
This is actually going to look so funny.
We're going to go to the end.
Broop!
To the end.
You'll see.
It's going to be hilarious.
Uh, so we, uh...
Watch this.
Did I just cut this?
Oh, it's still a funnel.
Okay.
Hey, hey, hey, hey, look at this!
Uh...
Yeah?
Uh, hold on.
Now we do here?
Need another wheel!
Wheel me!
Wheel, wheel, wheel, wheel, wheel, wheel, wheel, wheel, wheel.
Gear.
That cock!
Oh my god, this is going to be so sick.
Watch this.
No!
Not now!
It's still...
Nooo!
Worst time ever.
Uh, okay.
You, you, yeah.
There we go, there we go.
Good enough.
You ready?
Here we go!
Oh!
Wait, uh, tunnel.
Wait, what happened to it?
Oh.
Wait, it don't go in?!
What the hell is that?!
We need a Tottenholland.
Holland!
I need you.
This, this funnel doesn't work.
For some reason.
I don't know why.
I don't care.
That should work.
Ow!
It's fine.
Now.
In you go!
And... That,
that's insane!
What an elegant solution, and yet so devastatingly chaotic.
Look how fast it's cranking, too!
It's ready!
Every time!
And... Is it done?!
Wait, I don't wanna keep cutting it if it's done!
That's it!
No!
My axe!
Don't you dare cut my axe!
Look!
I need that!
I need... I think we got it!
I think we got what we need for the train!
I can't believe it!
Everyone calm down!
This is... This is it!
This is what we've been training for!
Literally!
Or not training yet, but we will.
Wow!
Very nice!
Uh... Engine assembly.
I need to see what I just got.
Uh... Some... Engine, right?
Oh my god.
Red portable engine.
But wait, how does that work?!
Blast furnace?
And... Dude, I have that!
No problem!
I guess I need to add oil to it, or... Like... Coal maybe, or...
I mean, it needs a fuel source, I guess.
It's not just... Going, is it?
That sounds crazy.
Uh...
I need, uh... What was it?
A blaster?
Blast, blast, blast?
How do I blast?
Three smooth stone.
Who has that?
Nobody just has three smooth stone.
Why is it not showing me what... Oh my god.
Okay, uh... Why did that not show me exactly what I need for it?
Okay.
Stone.
Got it.
One, two, three...
In you go.
This is gonna be insane.
I know it.
An iron sheet we have, and that's it, right?
A red portable engine.
I think we also need a furnace.
Not that one.
Give me this.
Really?!
We need cobblestone, or what?
Oh, okay.
Thank you!
Portable!
Iron ingots as well.
Oh no!
Wait, I have him!
Yes!
Oh, wait.
Blast first.
There we go, and now...
Engine!
Sick!
Hold on, I don't wanna ponder it yet.
I wanna see it first.
Fuel?
None.
I knew it.
I'm guessing we can put whatever fuel we normally put in a furnace, you know?
But let's see.
It generates rotational force by burning fuel.
Lovely!
Coal?
Yep!
Sick, man!
That is awesome!
It can be configured to run in either direction.
Oh, nice.
Very cool.
Fuel can be inserted by automated means.
Oh, okay.
Now you start to appreciate renewable energy.
So you don't have to do this, you know?
But I guess this makes sense for something like a train.
Using a blaze cake, the portable engine can be superheated for additional power output.
Alright.
Guess I'll make a blaze cake.
Nice.
That is incredible.
Unfortunately, there was nothing that popped up that sounded like a train.
I can't believe it.
Maybe I need to make some of these weird redstone thingies, actually.
Like, maybe a stock link or something.
I think I can make that.
No, I can't.
Transmitter, copper sheet, lightning rod.
I believe I needed that for that.
And copper sheet, I have not.
Damn.
Yes, I do!
What did I say?
Hmm...
Stock.
Item bolt.
But I also needed the transmission thingy.
I have it.
Yeah.
Stock link.
Oh!
Look at that!
Doesn't look like a train, though, but okay.
When placed, the stock links can...
Or create a new stock network.
Wait, really?
I can invest?
Right click an existing link before placing it to bind them.
What, these are antennas?
Or...
Stock linked packagers make their inventory available to the...
Wait, wait, wait, wait.
Are you saying?
Oh, that's insane if that's true.
You're saying I can have a central place with all my stuff?
And I can have little chests spread around?
Able to access it?
Whoa!
That is absolutely huge!
Other components on the network can now find and request their items.
Huh!
Maybe it's not instant, maybe it needs to be transported.
Packages?
Maybe.
Right?
Yeah, look!
On request, items from the inventories will be placed into packages.
Yeah?
Alright.
Stock link signals have unlimited range, but packages require transportation.
Yeah, how does that work then?
Full redstone power will stop a link from broadcasting.
Analog power lowers the priority of a link causing others to act first.
Yeah, okay, but...
How am I transporting the packages?
Drones?
Amazon delivery or something?
I don't know, don't they do drones nowadays?
I think that's only in the US.
Damn.
Well...
What's that sound?
Oh, it's because there's kids playing outside.
I kept hearing someone going...
And I thought it was Jackie, just singing.
Like she does.
But it's actually kids outside.
There's a little playground.
And it's...
Kind of annoying actually, that it's right outside my window, but you know.
It is what it is.
Small tires.
Fix all this.
We got the spring.
You know what would be really cool?
If wearing these glasses would allow me to...
Preview the chests.
You know what I mean?
Like I look inside and I go like a little preview of what's inside.
Ah, how would that even work?
I don't even know how that would work.
Yeah, that's probably a bad idea.
But yeah, I don't know.
I mean, I guess I put names on them, so it's fine.
Ah, never mind.
Bad idea.
Doesn't make sense.
The stock link though is kind of interesting.
This seems big.
Oh yeah, we also have a clockwork bearing.
To make a clock.
Good.
Well, I'm gonna ponder that.
Literally.
For next time.
Because we are close to trains.
I can feel it.
We are almost there.
But you know what?
I think we discovered a lot of new stuff today.
The elevator is now in full swing.
Literally.
We have an automated farm on top of the house.
Harvesting all kinds of goodies.
We have made a portable engine.
And we've experimented with assembling things in a sequence.
Which is awesome.
That is such a cool way of doing it, by the way.
So you have the belt system in place, you know.
And you want people to experiment with the belt and stuff.
So obviously you wanna have them use them.
What better way to do it than force them to make something in a sequence.
I think that's fantastic.
Love it.
What do you think?
Thinks Oliver should watch the eclipse.
Oh yeah, true!
Wait, isn't that, like, very soon?
I guess I'll find out when it becomes really dark.
Let me google it real quick.
Click again.
Real quick.
Eclipse.
Okay, it's not for another hour and ten minutes.
I have time.
I can't believe the game didn't give you an achievement for time traveling!
I know!
What are you- By the way!
How did that look to you guys?
That whole sequence.
I need to rewatch that.
I gotta see what happened there.
I think I- I think I banked my table.
Cause I was a little upsetty spaghetti at dying.
Walked out and that banging had apparently started the music and also crashed the game.
So I don't know...
It looked normal?
Really?
You got so angry you decided to invent a TARDIS.
Honestly, I wasn't really that angry.
It was more like, oh, come on.
Did I really do that again feeling?
It was more like a giant disappointment in myself.
That's what that was.
Good script, thank you.
We worked hard on this one.
I have a whole team of writers.
Magical banging?
What are you talking about?
Can you consider getting the apple skin mod?
What is that?
I'm not gonna add any more mods, I don't think.
Apple skin mod.
Food related HUD improvements?
I think I'm fine.
I don't need food related HUD improvements.
If anything, I need...
I don't know.
I need...
Just a better grasp on how to handle my inventory.
Just for saturation meter?
I don't even know what that is.
Did you finish the elevator?
Almost!
I mean, it's not exactly where I want it to be.
I still have a little hack installed, preventing it from going further up.
But there is most definitely a way to do it without that.
Especially if you have multiple levels that you want to get to with the elevator.
Let's say you want to go to the first floor.
You click one button.
A second floor, another button.
I'm gonna implement that at some point.
It's definitely possible, somehow.
Especially now that we know we can make, like, redstone over distances, right?
There's definitely a way to do it.
Spaghetti is the fate of every player of any factory game.
Yeah, at least at first.
But then, you know, you gotta get the basics down with the spaghetti.
And then when you have it down, then you can start to optimize the spaghetti.
Just like code, in real life.
The first time around, you know, you get it to work, barely.
You hold it together with duct tape and spit.
And then you ask yourself, okay, how do we make this nice now?
At least that's how I code.
If you try to optimize from the beginning, you're gonna end up doing a lot of work again and again.
I think you should forget about beauty this season, and focus on the sublime, industrial aesthetic of having shit everywhere.
I think that's pretty much what I'm practicing right now, though.
There is pretty much shit everywhere.
And it's getting worse as time goes on.
Or better, depending on how you look at it.
It's part of the charm.
That's what I keep saying, right?
It's not perfect.
It's not elegant.
It's not smooth.
It's sort of distorted and messed up and dirty.
On purpose.
Stalk Link made me happy.
Good.
Made me happy too.
Add the horse crushing create add-on.
There's a create add-on for crushing horses?
Damn.
Someone must really hate horses that they went through all the trouble of making an add-on for it.
I think it makes glue.
Oh, I guess...
Yeah, you do use horses for glue.
That's a real thing.
And apparently you also use horses for licorice.
We make licorice in Denmark out of horses.
Not kidding.
We compress them until they taste good.
Salty sweets.
Oh yeah.
Super nice.
I love the candy add-ons.
There's candy.
Can you become a chocolatier?
That would fit very well with the factory.
Willy Wonka.
I mean, I can already make chocolate, right?
Apparently.
There's a bucket of chocolate.
I'm guessing all I need is some sugar and some cocoa.
Isn't that...
Wait, what else goes into chocolate?
Cocoa, sugar, maybe water?
Something like that.
And some other stuff.
A bunch of additives, obviously.
There's an add-on that adds roller coasters?
I'm not surprised.
That's one of the first things I thought of.
Makes sense.
The create crafters were made before the vanilla crafters.
Really?
Wait, remind me, guys.
Did the crafter in Minecraft come out while I was playing?
Or was that already out when I started playing for the first time?
Because create is not that old, is it?
Maybe it's like eight years?
Seven?
No, I don't know, actually.
While you played.
Okay.
Damn, that's recent then.
Yeah.
Makes sense.
Create had a lot of stuff before Minecraft.
Like copper.
Really?
So did they have different icons for the copper, or what?
Like, how did that work?
Wait, hold on.
Minecraft has always had copper.
Unless you're talking about copper swords and stuff.
Right?
Unless you're... oh, okay.
Shit.
I don't know my Minecraft history, I'm sorry.
Copper was added in 1.17...
Okay, but I don't know when that was.
Huh.
So, you're talking about the actual just copper ingots and stuff.
That's...
Something that was added quite late in Minecraft?
I got the impression that was something that would have been there since the beginning.
I did check, by the way, and apparently the fluid stuff is fine.
So...
Yeah.
Like, the recipes are there.
Frogs, copper, spears, trial chambers, all new.
Yeah.
Wait, frogs are new?
I guess the frogs do kind of have a little...
modern...
model to it.
Compared to some of the other animals, like sheep or cows.
Or maybe not.
Maybe I'm imagining...
Maybe I'm just thinking that since you just said it, you know?
I'm not sure, actually.
They realized no one used copper and added copper tools and armor.
Yeah, I'm surprised that wasn't a thing immediately when they added copper.
That just seems like the natural thing to do.
What's this music?
It's from Persona 5.
Once again, it has all the banger tracks.
This one is called...
Have a short rest.
Copper got added in 2021.
What?!
That's like a year before I started playing.
Or maybe...
One and a half years...
Ish.
What the hell, really?
But there are so many recipes that require copper.
So what did you do before that?
Did you not have the, uh...
The lightning rod or...
The copper blocks, I guess?
And all the other stuff that requires copper.
No spyglass.
Oh my god!
Wow.
I'm so happy I started playing after they added copper then.
Imagine not having a spyglass.
That would suck.
I guess I wouldn't have known.
You don't know any better.
I'm surprised Jackie hasn't been pestering me about food.
Normally she's all over me right now.
Hm.
A lot of people use the mod called Optifine for Zoom anyway.
Oh.
I see.
Have you even used a spyglass this season yet?
Oh yeah.
Not as much as I have earlier.
But that's because I've been mostly building.
But I got it.
You can extend this mod with the factory must grow.
But I'm just gonna keep it as it is, guys.
It's gonna be simple.
Create.
With the create add-on called Aeronautics and all that.
That I have right now.
That's it.
I mean, already it's overwhelming, guys.
Adding way more on top of it is just gonna...
I think it's gonna detract.
For me.
Jade mod could let you preview the item in the chest.
Also tell you what you're looking at.
Oh, so there is a way to do that.
That's fun.
So it was kind of a good idea I had.
I just felt like it would be a little...
Weird how that would look.
Like it wouldn't quite fit into the Minecraft aesthetic, I guess.
But then again, I haven't seen how they do it in that mod.
So maybe it's done very tastefully and in line with the game.
But who knows.
I can't believe we still haven't gotten the full windmill yet.
I think it would be nearly impossible to play Minecraft blind without the recipe book.
I think you are completely right.
Like how on earth are you even going to...
Do some things.
Like without...
You would have to...
Yeah, that's impossible.
That's straight up impossible, I think.
Well, technically it ain't.
You know, but still.
You can, you know, reason your way to some things.
Like, you know, a pickaxe has a certain shape or a door or whatever.
But the thing is, you wouldn't even know to make those.
You don't know what's in the game, right?
It's impossible, I guess.
Did you see eyeshow speed and Kai's challenge that they're doing?
No?
Is it related to Minecraft?
I may have heard that they're doing something Minecraft related.
I think you're talking about that.
I haven't seen it though.
Is it good?
I can't believe...
I can't even imagine playing without a recipe book.
I guess if I did, I would remember more recipes by heart, you know?
But now I'm just...
I'm using the book every time because...
Yeah, I don't know.
There's so many recipes to keep track of.
They're trying to kill all four bosses in hardcore.
Wait, four bosses.
So we have the dragon.
Another one's gotta be the wither.
Maybe the guy from...
The green place.
Uh...
I forget his name.
Warden, I think?
That's three.
And the last one...
Uh...
Wait, what's the last one?
Elder Guardian?
I don't even know what that is.
No idea what that is.
Oh!
The big...
Oh, the big fish!
Okay, yeah, yeah.
Got it, got it.
Okay, the FaceTime guy.
Right.
Makes sense.
Damn, in hardcore?
I guess they're playing multiplayer then.
It's gonna make it easier, but...
That sounds difficult.
I would die a lot.
You would have to prepare a lot, I guess.
The FaceTime guy.
I didn't say it, you guys said it.
Down, down, down.
Before Recipe Book and with Google, I was memorizing and studying recipes.
Yeah, I can imagine.
Like, I...
When we watch those speedrun videos...
Nobody's using the recipe book, of course.
They're all just...
You know?
And then everything's crafted.
And I barely saw what they did.
Maybe one of these days I'm gonna...
I'm gonna do the same, you know?
Maybe one of these days I'm gonna get the world record in Minecraft speedrun.
I couldn't even say that with a straight face.
Just kidding.
But it would be fun to try.
Just to see if I could get a good time, you know?
Like a personal best or something.
They use book for speedruns.
I guess complicated recipes would be easier with the book.
Some things like making a crafting table would be easier just to brrrt, you know?
There's a song called...
How do I craft this again?
About forgetting memorizing recipes.
Oh!
I thought you were about to say that there's a song.
Like a memo-type song that's...
It's like saying...
Oh, be a fine girl, kiss me lovingly.
For O-B-A-F-G-K-M type stars.
You know, like...
What is the word for those things?
A memo...
Memorization technique...
I forget.
Mnemonic.
That's it, that's it, yeah.
Maybe you guys have a mnemonic for all the items.
Better be a good one to remember all of them.
Like up, up, right, down, left, up, right, and then with all the items.
That's gonna be a crazy one.
Have you played Minecraft 1.12.2?
That is such a random question.
I have no idea.
My answer is probably no.
I don't even...
Like, aren't there like a million different versions?
That is a crazy question.
And so specific as well.
Why not 1.12.4?
Or 1, or 1.11.9, or...
Why that one specifically?
That's so specific.
1.12.4 doesn't exist?
How do you know that off the top?
There's no way you knew that.
Or maybe you did.
Alright, alright, alright.
Are you gonna play Minecraft Vanilla again in a future season?
Yeah, but it's probably gonna be like a speedrun thing.
Because I think I wanna try that at some point.
I think it could be a fun little minigame to try and optimize that, you know?
No, not hardcore.
It would just be like whatever normal speedrun...
strat is, you know what I mean?
Would you speedrun blind?
Well...
Not with a blindfold, but...
I mean, I know the game already.
I know what to do to get to the end.
So I guess I would just try and optimize that.
Yeah.
You need that scary F3 menu for speedrunning.
But isn't there a category for not using that?
People told me that.
That's what I wanna go for.
I don't wanna be using frickin' NASA tools to speedrun.
I just wanna play the damn game.
Without going into a debug menu or calculating the circumference of a fuckin'...
I don't know, I don't even know, like, four-dimensional...
something, something.
I wanna see you make an insane boiler house for all the world's cranking needs.
It's gonna happen!
I intend to boil orphans.
Hahaha!
It's gonna be a combined orphan boiler.
And on top of that, we're gonna use...
the power and the steam to power all my other engines.
It's gonna be good.
There is a category for that.
Yeah, that's what I'm saying.
That's what I would go for.
It just sounds more fun to me, I guess.
But I haven't tried the other one, so maybe it is fun.
It's just my initial...
feeling about it, is that it probably wouldn't be as...
much fun for me, personally.
But, who knows?
Maybe it would be.
Me and the boys, bulk boiling orphans.
BULK BOILING!
Why is that not a thing?
Beautiful.
Guys, I'm gonna cut the ripcord.
I'm off.
I'll see you around.
Also, by the way, uh...
Detroit Become Human won the vote.
So that's coming up soon on the channel.
For, uh...
offline recording.
So yeah.
Some people have been asking for that for a while, so now it's finally happening.
Detroit Become Human.
And yeah.
Maybe also another stream game soon.
That we're gonna run at the same time as Minecraft.
Have a good one.
Ciao!